<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sexual Scandals in the Vatican II Sect on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/sexual-scandals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sexual Scandals in the Vatican II Sect on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:59:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/sexual-scandals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Idolatry Of The Vatican II Sect &amp; Its Rampant Homosexuality</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/sexual-scandals/the-idolatry-of-the-vatican-ii-sect-its-rampant-homosexuality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:59:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/sexual-scandals/the-idolatry-of-the-vatican-ii-sect-its-rampant-homosexuality/</guid>
      <description>Scripture teaches that homosexuality is a result of idolatry. Romans 1- “Because that, when they knew God, they have not glorified him as God, or given thanks; but became vain in their thoughts, and their foolish heart was darkened... who changed the truth of God into a lie; and worshipped and served the creature rather than the Creator, who is blessed for ever. Amen. For this cause God delivered them up to shameful affections.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New “Catholic” Seminaries And Homosexuality</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/sexual-scandals/the-new-catholic-seminaries-and-homosexuality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:58:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/sexual-scandals/the-new-catholic-seminaries-and-homosexuality/</guid>
      <description>Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Pope Pius XI, Ad catholici sacerdotii (# 66), Dec. 20, 1935: “Give the best of your clergy to your seminaries; do not fear to take them from other positions.&amp;nbsp; These [other] positions may seem of greater moment, but in reality their importance is not to be compared with that of the seminaries, which is capital and indispensable.&amp;nbsp; Seek also from elsewhere, wherever you can find them, men really fitted for this noble task.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sexual Scandals Committed By “Priests” Of The Vatican II Sect</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/sexual-scandals/sexual-scandals-committed-by-priests-of-the-vatican-ii-sect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:56:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/sexual-scandals/sexual-scandals-committed-by-priests-of-the-vatican-ii-sect/</guid>
      <description>“Cardinal” Bernard Law, formerly of Boston, who presided over the Vatican II sect’s massive sexual scandal there&#xA;CBS News - Clergy members and others in the Boston Archdiocese likely sexually abused more than 1,000 people over a period of six decades, Massachusetts&#39; attorney general said Wednesday, calling the scandal so massive it &#34;borders on the unbelievable.&#34;[1]&#xA;Almost everyone reading this book is probably familiar with the massive sexual scandal among Novus Ordo/Vatican II “priests” that was unceasingly exposed by the mainstream media from approximately 2002-2004.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
