<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Against the Co-Redemptrix heresy on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-co-redemptrix/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Against the Co-Redemptrix heresy on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 06:15:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-co-redemptrix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mary is not the Co-Redeemer (Co-Redemptrix)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-co-redemptrix/mary-is-not-the-co-redeemer-co-redemptrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 06:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-co-redemptrix/mary-is-not-the-co-redeemer-co-redemptrix/</guid>
      <description>Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;It&#39;s an infallibly defined dogma that Jesus Christ alone is the Redeemer.&#xA;Pope Pius IV,&amp;nbsp;Council of Trent, Sess. 25, On Invocation, Veneration and Relics of Saints, and on Sacred Images,&amp;nbsp;ex cathedra: “…&amp;nbsp;the saints, who reign with Christ, offer up their prayers to God for men; and that it is good and useful to invoke them suppliantly and, in order to obtain favors from God through His Son&amp;nbsp;JESUS CHRIST OUR LORD, WHO ALONE IS OUR REDEEMER&amp;nbsp;and Savior… And they must also teach that images of Christ,&amp;nbsp;the virgin mother of God and the other saints should be set up and kept… But if anyone should teach or maintain anything contrary to these decrees, let him be anathema.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Mary Co-Redemptrix? No. Here’s Why.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-co-redemptrix/is-mary-co-redemptrix-no-heres-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 06:13:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-co-redemptrix/is-mary-co-redemptrix-no-heres-why/</guid>
      <description>Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Refuting a Response on Co-Redemptrix; defending the necessity of devotion to Our Lady; and defending the truth that Jesus Christ is our Sole Redeemer FOR A MORE UPDATED ARTICLE ON THIS MATTER, SEE THIS:&#xA;Mary is not the Co-Redeemer (Co-Redemptrix) [Dennis M. sent out an e-mail complaining that our answer that Mary is not Co-Redemptrix is wrong. He writes:]&#xA;This latest posting from the MHFM website - run by Peter and Michael Dimond - seems to show forth their absence of the proper understanding of Our Lady as Co-Redemptrix.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
