<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Answers to Objections on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Answers to Objections on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bayside, Medjugorje and Other False Apparitions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/20-bayside-medjugorje-and-other-false-apparitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/20-bayside-medjugorje-and-other-false-apparitions/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION- Our Lady herself revealed at Bayside and Medjugorje that non-Catholics can be saved, so you are wrong.&#xA;“Our Lady” of Bayside, August 14, 1979: “Do not judge your brothers and sisters who have not been converted.&amp;nbsp; For My Father’s House, My Son has repeated over and over, remember always – that in My Father’s House, there are many rooms in the Mansion, signifying faiths and creeds.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cornelius The Centurion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/15-cornelius-the-centurion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/15-cornelius-the-centurion/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION- Acts 10:47 says that Cornelius and his companions received the Holy Ghost.&amp;nbsp; This means that they were justified without Baptism.&#xA;ANSWER- Acts 10:47 does not say that Cornelius and his companions were justified without Baptism.&amp;nbsp; Nothing there says that their sins were remitted or that they were “saved,” a phrase frequently used to describe those who have been justified by Baptism.&amp;nbsp; The context of Acts 10 is dealing with receiving the Holy Ghost by receiving the gift of speaking in tongues, not having one’s sins remitted.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Can Baptism Of Desire Be Contrary To Dogma When...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/14-baptism-of-desire-contrary-to-dogma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/14-baptism-of-desire-contrary-to-dogma/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION- How can baptism of desire be contrary to dogma when a saint such as St. Alphonsus believed in it after the Council of Trent? That would make him a heretic, which is impossible since he is a canonized saint.&#xA;ANSWER- First, the key to heresy is obstinacy/pertinacity. It is a fact that a man (if he is not obstinate) could hold a position that is heretical, such as the idea that Christ only has one will, without being a heretic (unless the man came to depart from the essential belief in the Trinity and Incarnation; in that case, even if he were not obstinate, he would lose the Catholic Faith).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Invincible Ignorance Becomes A Destructive Heresy,</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/02-invincible-ignorance-heresy/03-invincible-ignorance-destructive-heresy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/02-invincible-ignorance-heresy/03-invincible-ignorance-destructive-heresy/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;The heresy that non-Catholics can be saved by “invincible ignorance” wasn’t really a problem before the year 1800, since the teaching of Catholic Tradition that no one can be saved who is ignorant of the Gospel was quite clear and maintained by most. But thanks to the growing modernism in the 1850’s, combined with the liberals’ hijacking of Pope Pius IX’s weak statements, the heretical theory of salvation for the invincibly ignorant exploded and became the belief of many priests in the latter half of the 19th century and the first half of the 20th century.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jesus Christ Against Invincible Ignorance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/02-invincible-ignorance-heresy/08-jesus-christ-against-invincible-ignorance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/02-invincible-ignorance-heresy/08-jesus-christ-against-invincible-ignorance/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Perhaps nothing in the New Testament is as clear as the fact that Our Lord Jesus Christ is the Son of God, and that you must believe in Him to have eternal life.&#xA;John 3:16: “For God so loved the world, as to give His only begotten Son: that whosoever believeth in Him, may not perish, but may have life everlasting.”&#xA;John 3:36: “He that believeth in the Son hath life everlasting: but he that believeth not the Son, shall not see life, but the wrath of God abideth on him.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Other Popes And Saints Against Invincible Ignorance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/02-invincible-ignorance-heresy/05-saints-against-invincible-ignorance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/02-invincible-ignorance-heresy/05-saints-against-invincible-ignorance/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Defenders of salvation for the “invincibly ignorant” might be disquieted to hear that two other popes, Pope Benedict XIV and Pope St. Pius X, explicitly reiterated the Church’s dogma that there are certain mysteries of faith about which no one who wishes to be saved can be ignorant. These mysteries are the mysteries of the Trinity and the Incarnation, as it was defined by the Athanasian Creed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pope Innocent II</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/06-pope-innocent-ii-baptism-of-desire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/06-pope-innocent-ii-baptism-of-desire/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION- Pope Innocent II taught that a priest could be saved without the Sacrament of Baptism by his desire for it and his confession of the true faith (Denzinger 388): “To your inquiry we respond thus: We assert without hesitation (on the authority of the holy fathers Augustine and Ambrose) that the priest whom you indicated (in your letter) had died without the water of baptism, because he persevered in the faith of holy mother Church and in the confession of the name of Christ, was freed from original sin and attained the joy of the heavenly fatherland.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pope Innocent III</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/07-pope-innocent-iii-baptism-of-desire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/07-pope-innocent-iii-baptism-of-desire/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION-&amp;nbsp; Pope Innocent III taught that a person who baptized himself could be saved by the desire for the Sacrament of Baptism.&#xA;Pope Innocent III, to the Bishop of Metz, Aug. 28, 1206: “We respond that, since there should be a distinction between the one baptizing and the one baptized, as is clearly gathered from the words of the Lord, when he says to the Apostles: ‘Go, baptize all nations in the name etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pope Pius IX Did Not Teach Salvation Outside The Church</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/02-invincible-ignorance-heresy/02-pope-pius-ix-salvation-dogma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/02-invincible-ignorance-heresy/02-pope-pius-ix-salvation-dogma/</guid>
      <description>Singulari Quadame and Quanto Conficiamur Moerore are discussed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sacred Scripture Against Invincible Ignorance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/02-invincible-ignorance-heresy/06-sacred-scripture-against-invincible-ignorance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/02-invincible-ignorance-heresy/06-sacred-scripture-against-invincible-ignorance/</guid>
      <description>And The Evidence of The Immediate Dissemination of The Gospel throughout The World.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Salvation For The “Invincibly Ignorant” Reduced To Its Absurd Principle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/02-invincible-ignorance-heresy/07-invincible-ignorance-absurd-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/02-invincible-ignorance-heresy/07-invincible-ignorance-absurd-principle/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;The theory that “invincible ignorance” saves can also be refuted by reducing it to its absurd principle, which is this: If being ignorant of the Savior could render one worthy of salvation, then Catholics are actually doing non-Christians a disservice in preaching Jesus Christ to them. St. Paul, St. Vincent Ferrer, St. Francis Xavier, Fr. Pierre De Smet, the North American Martyrs and the other countless heroic missionaries in Church history, who suffered mind-boggling hardships to preach the Gospel to the ignorant pagans, were simply making these people more culpable and more guilty before God, according to the modern heresy of salvation for the “invincibly ignorant.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sess. 7, Can. 4 On The Sacraments</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/05-sess-7-can-4-on-the-sacraments-trent/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/05-sess-7-can-4-on-the-sacraments-trent/</guid>
      <description>Actually Refutes Baptism of Desire, as Can Be Seen When Compared with Similar Dogmatic Canons on The Sacraments in General.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>St. Alphonsus’ Blatant Error on ‘Baptism of Desire’</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/08-st-alphonsus-blatant-error-on-baptism-of-desire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/08-st-alphonsus-blatant-error-on-baptism-of-desire/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Supporters of ‘baptism of desire’ are fond of quoting St. Alphonsus’ opinion on the issue. In our video, Baptism of Desire Buried (linked below), we carefully discuss it. We not only demonstrate that St. Alphonsus’ explanation of BOD (i.e., ‘baptism of desire’) is riddled with problems, but that it would have to be rejected even by ‘baptism of desire’ supporters. Many supporters of ‘BOD,’ however, didn’t seem to notice or grasp the significance of the point made in the video on that particular issue.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The “Private Interpretation” Objection</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/03-private-interpretation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/03-private-interpretation/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION- You are acting like a Protestant. The Protestant privately interprets Sacred Scripture, while you privately interpret dogmatic statements.&#xA;ANSWER- This objection was refuted in Section 2 of this document, “Believe Dogma As It Was Once Declared.”&#xA;Pope Pius IX, First Vatican Council, Sess. 3, Chap. 2 on Revelation, 1870, ex cathedra: “Hence, also, that understanding of its sacred dogmas must be perpetually retained, which Holy Mother Church has once declared; and there must never be a recession from that meaning under the specious name of a deeper understanding.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The “Within but Not A Member” Objection of Msgr. Fenton</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/19-within-but-not-a-member-fenton/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/19-within-but-not-a-member-fenton/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION- In his book The Catholic Church and Salvation, Msgr. Joseph Clifford Fenton points out that, while only the baptized are actual members of the Church, one can be “within” or “inside” the Church without being a member.&amp;nbsp; Thus, the unbaptized can be saved without being members of the Catholic Church because they can still be “inside.”&#xA;&amp;nbsp;Pope Pius XII, Mystici Corporis (# 22), June 29, 1943:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; “Actually only those are to be numbered among the members of the Church who have received the laver of regeneration and profess the true faith.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The “You Can’t Judge” Heresy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/17-you-cant-judge-heresy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/17-you-cant-judge-heresy/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION- You can’t judge if all non-Catholics go to Hell. You are not God. You must leave such judgments to Him.&#xA;ANSWER- God has already revealed His judgment to us. To say that one cannot be sure or “cannot judge” if all who die as non-Catholics go to hell is simply to reject God’s judgment as possibly untrue, which is heresy and blasphemy and pride of the worst kind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 1917 Code of Canon Law</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/11-1917-code-of-canon-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/11-1917-code-of-canon-law/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;John 3:5 Mockers Stumped (1917 Code, Delayed Ensoulment, “Baptism Of Desire”) THE VIDEO ABOVE IS A MUST-SEE VIDEO ON THIS MATTER&#xA;OBJECTION- The 1917 Code of Canon Law gives Christian Burial to unbaptized catechumens and teaches baptism of desire.&#xA;ANSWER- As we’ve pointed out before, the 1917 Code of Canon Law is not infallible. The 1917 Code was definitely not an ex cathedra (from the Chair of Peter) pronouncement because it does not bind the whole Church, but only the Latin Church (not the Eastern Rites), as stipulated in Canon 1 of the 1917 Code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Argument from Silence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/10-argument-from-silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/10-argument-from-silence/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION- If it is true that there is no such thing as baptism of desire or baptism of blood, then why didn’t any pope come out and condemn these theories as they were appearing in so many catechisms in the late 1800’s and following?&#xA;ANSWER- Baptism of desire and baptism of blood are shown in various ways to be excluded by the infallible teaching of the Catholic Church.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Argument That Baptism Is Impossible For Some To Receive</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/12-baptism-not-impossible-to-receive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/12-baptism-not-impossible-to-receive/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION-&amp;nbsp; Baptism of desire supporters assert that for some people the command to be baptized is simply impossible to fulfill.&#xA;ANSWER- God does not command impossibilities (de fide).&amp;nbsp; Thus, it is not impossible for any man to get baptized.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;Catechism of the Council of Trent, On Baptism, Tan Books, p. 171:&#xA;&#34;Holy writers are unanimous in saying that after the Resurrection of our Lord, WHEN HE GAVE HIS APOSTLES THE COMMAND to go and teach all nations: baptizing them in the name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Ghost, THE LAW OF BAPTISM became obligatory on all who were to be saved.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Brown Scapular</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/21-the-brown-scapular/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/21-the-brown-scapular/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION- Our Lady said that whoever dies wearing the Brown Scapular will not go to Hell. This means that you are wrong: non-Catholics and the unbaptized can be saved who die wearing the Scapular.&#xA;ANSWER- Everyone should wear the Brown Scapular; it is a sign of devotion to Our Lady and a powerful sacramental. And we too originally believed that whoever dies wearing the Brown Scapular could not go to Hell.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Catechism of Trent and “Baptism of Desire”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/04-catechism-of-trent-baptism-of-desire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/04-catechism-of-trent-baptism-of-desire/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION- The Catechism of the Council of Trent taught that the design and plan of receiving Baptism could avail a person to grace and righteousness, if it is impossible for that person to receive Baptism. That means that “baptism of desire” must be Catholic teaching.&#xA;Catechism of the Council of Trent, “Ordinarily They Are Not Baptized At Once,” p. 179: “But though these things may be thus, nevertheless to this class [or kind] of men [persons], the Church has not been accustomed to give the Sacrament of Baptism at once, but has arranged that it should be deferred to a fixed time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Council Of Trent Did Not Teach &#34;Baptism Of Desire&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/01-council-of-trent-did-not-teach-baptism-of-desire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/01-council-of-trent-did-not-teach-baptism-of-desire/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Some people think that baptism of desire is taught by the Council of Trent in Sess. 6, Chap 4 on justification. This video will show why they are wrong. It will also cover some very important new points and quotes. The passage says:&#xA;Pope Paul III, Council of Trent, Sess. 6, Chap. 4: “In these words there is conveyed a description of the justification of the impious, how there is a transition from that state in which a person is born as a child of the first Adam to the state of grace and of adoption as sons of God through the second Adam, Jesus Christ our savior; indeed, this transition, after the Gospel has been promulgated, CANNOT TAKE PLACE WITHOUT the laver of regeneration or a desire for it, AS IT IS WRITTEN: Unless a man is born again of water and the Holy Spirit, he cannot enter the kingdom of God (John 3:5).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Dogma, Pope Pius IX And Invincible Ignorance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/02-invincible-ignorance-heresy/01-dogma-pope-pius-ix-invincible-ignorance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/02-invincible-ignorance-heresy/01-dogma-pope-pius-ix-invincible-ignorance/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION- What about Invincible Ignorance?&#xA;ANSWER-&amp;nbsp;&#xA;2 Corinthians 4:3: “And if our gospel be hid, it is hid to them that are lost, in whom the god of this world [Satan] hath blinded the minds of unbelievers, that the light of the gospel of the glory of Christ, who is the image of God, should not shine unto them.”&amp;nbsp;&#xA;Pope Paul III, Council of Trent, Sess.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Errors of Michael Du Bay</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/13-errors-of-michael-du-bay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/13-errors-of-michael-du-bay/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION- Wasn’t the idea that catechumens cannot have the remission of sins condemned in the Errors of Michael Du Bay?&#xA;ANSWER- No!&amp;nbsp; And the fact that certain baptism of desire advocates obstinately attempt to quote the Errors of Michael Du Bay in favor of baptism of desire simply shows: 1) their dishonesty; and 2) their lack of evidence for “baptism of desire.”&#xA;Errors of Michael Du Bay, Condemned by St.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Good Thief and The Holy Innocents</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/16-good-thief-holy-innocents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/16-good-thief-holy-innocents/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;ANSWER- This was addressed already in the section on St. Augustine, but it will be repeated here for those who may be looking for it in this section of “Other Objections.” The Good Thief cannot be used as an example of baptism of blood primarily because the Good Thief died under the Old Law, not the New Law; he died before the Law of Baptism was instituted by Jesus Christ after the Resurrection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Objective-Subjective Heresy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/18-the-objective-subjective-heresy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/18-the-objective-subjective-heresy/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION- Objectively speaking, there is absolutely no salvation outside the Catholic Church. But subjectively speaking, we just don’t know.&#xA;ANSWER- This is similar to the “You Can’t Judge” heresy. Those who advance this heresy deny dogmatic truth; for the Objective-Subjective Heresy means that the dogma Outside the Church There is No Salvation is only true “objectively,” which necessarily means that non-Catholics can be saved “subjectively,” which means that the end result is a denial of the defined dogma.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Soul of the Church Heresy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/22-soul-of-the-church-heresy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/22-soul-of-the-church-heresy/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION- It’s possible to belong to the “Soul” of the Church without belonging to her Body. In this way those who die as members of non-Catholic religions can be joined to the Church and saved, as the Baltimore Catechism (1921) explains:&#xA;Q. 512 How are such persons said to belong to the Church?&#xA;A. Such persons are said to belong to the “Soul of the Church”; that is, they are really members of the Church without knowing it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trent’s Teaching on The Necessity of Penance vs. its Teaching on the Necessity of Baptism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/09-trent-necessity-of-penance-vs-baptism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/19-objections/09-trent-necessity-of-penance-vs-baptism/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION- I know that the Council of Trent defines in Canon 5 on the Sacrament of Baptism that the Sacrament of Baptism is necessary for salvation.&amp;nbsp; But the Council of Trent says that the necessity of the Sacrament of Penance is the same as that of Baptism, and that people can be justified without the Sacrament of Penance.&#xA;Pope Paul III, The Council of Trent, canons on the Sacrament of Baptism, canon 5, ex cathedra: “If anyone says that baptism [the Sacrament] is optional, that is, not necessary for salvation (cf.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
