<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>“Baptism” of Desire and of Blood (Heresies) on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/</link>
    <description>Recent content in “Baptism” of Desire and of Blood (Heresies) on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Baptism of Desire&#34; in The Middle Ages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/16-baptism-of-desire-in-the-middle-ages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/16-baptism-of-desire-in-the-middle-ages/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Now that we have shown that the teaching of Tradition is definitely not in favor of baptism of desire, where did this baptism of desire furor that we now see come from? Why did it become such a widespread belief later on? It has never been taught by any council, dogmatic definition or Papal Encyclical to the whole Church. But most people today think that it is a teaching of the Catholic Church.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baptism of Blood and Baptism of Desire – Erroneous Traditions of Man</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/01-water-baptism-church-fathers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/01-water-baptism-church-fathers/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;In this document, I have shown that the Catholic Church infallibly teaches that the Sacrament of Baptism is necessary for salvation.&amp;nbsp; I have also shown that it is only through receiving the Sacrament of Baptism that one is incorporated into the Catholic Church, outside of which there is no salvation.&amp;nbsp; I have also shown that the Catholic Church infallibly teaches that the words of Jesus Christ in John 3:5 – Amen, amen I say unto thee, unless a man be born again of water and the Holy Ghost, he cannot enter into the kingdom of God – are to be understood literally: as they are written.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Liturgical Tradition and Apostolic Burial Tradition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/14-liturgical-tradition-and-apostolic-burial-tradition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/14-liturgical-tradition-and-apostolic-burial-tradition/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Besides these clear testimonies of the fathers against the theory of baptism of desire, perhaps most striking is the fact that in the history of the Catholic Church there is not a single tradition that can be cited for praying for – or giving ecclesiastical burial to – catechumens who died without baptism.&amp;nbsp; The Catholic Encyclopedia (1907) had the following to say about the actual Tradition of the Church in this regard:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Miraculous Baptisms</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/08-miraculous-baptisms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/08-miraculous-baptisms/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;There would be no need for God to save anyone by baptism of blood (or “baptism of desire”), since He can keep any sincere souls alive until they are baptized, as we saw with the case of St. Alban and the converted guard. St. Martin of Tours brought back to life a catechumen who had died so that he could baptize him.[1] St. Joan of Arc brought back to life a dead infant so that she could baptize him.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pope St. Leo The Great Ends The Debate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/21-pope-leo-the-great-water-baptism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/21-pope-leo-the-great-water-baptism/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;We have seen how Tradition doesn’t teach baptism of desire and how the infallible teaching of the Church on the Sacrament of Baptism and John 3:5 excludes it. And we have seen how this error was perpetuated in the middle ages through flawed passages in the fallible texts of Churchmen. I will now discuss perhaps the most interesting pronouncement on this issue, the dogmatic letter of Pope St.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>St. Alban and His Converted Guard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/06-st-alban-and-his-converted-guard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/06-st-alban-and-his-converted-guard/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;St. Alban was the protomartyr of England (303 A.D.) The account of his martyrdom is particularly interesting and instructive on this topic. On the way to his martyrdom, one of the guards who led him to execution was converted to Christ. The Roman Martyrology (a fallible document), as well as Butler’s Lives of the Saints, says that the guard was “baptized in his own blood.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>St. Ambrose and &#34;Baptism of Desire&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/11-st-ambrose-and-baptism-of-desire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/11-st-ambrose-and-baptism-of-desire/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Out of the hundreds of fathers of the Church, the only other one that the baptism of desire advocates even try to quote is St. Ambrose. They think that in his funeral speech for his friend (the Emperor Valentinian) he taught that the emperor (who was only a catechumen) was saved by his desire for baptism. But St. Ambrose’s funeral speech for Valentinian is extremely ambiguous and could be interpreted in a variety of ways.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>St. Augustine and &#34;Baptism of Desire&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/10-st-augustine-and-baptism-of-desire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/10-st-augustine-and-baptism-of-desire/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;St. Augustine is quoted in favor of the concept of baptism of desire, but he admittedly struggled with the issue, sometimes clearly opposing the idea that unbaptized catechumens could achieve salvation, and other times supporting it.&#xA;St. Augustine, 400: “That the place of Baptism is sometimes supplied by suffering is supported by a substantial argument which the same Blessed Cyprian draws…Considering this over and over again, I find that not only suffering for the name of Christ can supply for that which is lacking by way of Baptism, but even faith and conversion of heart, if… recourse cannot be had to the celebration of the Mystery of Baptism.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>St. Bernard &amp; &#34;Baptism of Desire&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/17-st-bernard-baptism-of-desire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/17-st-bernard-baptism-of-desire/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;St. Bernard, Tractatus de baptismo, II, 8, c. 1130: “So, believe me, it would be difficult to turn me aside from these two pillars – I mean Augustine and Ambrose. I confess that, whether in error or knowledge, I am with them; for I believe that a man can be saved by faith alone, provided he desires to receive the sacrament, in a case where death overtakes the fulfillment of his religious desire, or some other invincible power stands in his way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>St. Gregory Nazianz and &#34;Baptism of Desire&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/12-st-gregory-nazianz-and-baptism-of-desire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/12-st-gregory-nazianz-and-baptism-of-desire/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;It is fitting also to look at the teaching of some of the other fathers. St. Gregory Nazianz is one of the four great Eastern Doctors of the Catholic Church. He explicitly rejected the concept of baptism of desire.&#xA;St. Gregory Nazianz, 381 AD: “Of those who fail to be baptized some are utterly animal and bestial, according to whether they are foolish or wicked.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>St. John Chrysostom &amp; &#34;Baptism of Desire&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/13-st-john-chrysostom-baptism-of-desire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/13-st-john-chrysostom-baptism-of-desire/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Besides St. Gregory and the others, St. John Chrysostom provides us with a plethora of quotations explicitly against the idea of salvation for unbaptized catechumens (those preparing to be baptized) by baptism of desire.&amp;nbsp; That anyone else besides unbaptized catechumens could qualify for salvation without first receiving the Sacrament of Baptism was not even considered a possibility worth refuting in this context. (How horrified would these fathers be by the modern version of the theory of baptism of desire, which saves pagans, Jews, heretics and schismatics?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>St. Thomas Aquinas &amp; “Baptism of Desire”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/18-st-thomas-aquinas-baptism-of-desire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/18-st-thomas-aquinas-baptism-of-desire/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;St. Thomas Aquinas, despite all of his fabulous writing and learning about the Catholic Faith, being a fallible human being, was wrong on many points, including his explicit statement in the Summa Theologica that “The flesh of the Virgin was conceived in Original Sin.”[1] One scholar noted that the book St. Thomas was writing when he died was called The Compendium of Theology, in which are found at least nine explicit errors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>St. Thomas Aquinas Rejected “Invincible Ignorance”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/20-st-thomas-aquinas-rejected-invincible-ignorance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/20-st-thomas-aquinas-rejected-invincible-ignorance/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;It is also very important to point out that while St. Thomas Aquinas was wrong on baptism of desire, he held the dogma Outside the Church There is No Salvation and rejected the modern day heresy that people can be saved who are “invincibly ignorant” of Jesus Christ. In numerous places St. Thomas directly addressed the question of persons in so-called invincible ignorance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summarizing The Facts On Baptism Of Blood</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/07-baptism-of-blood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/07-baptism-of-blood/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;As stated already, the theory of baptism of blood has never been taught by one pope, one council or in any Papal Encyclical.&amp;nbsp; At least 5 dogmatic councils of the Catholic Church issued detailed definitions on Baptism, and not one ever mentioned the concept or the term baptism of blood.&amp;nbsp; The Council of Trent had 14 canons on Baptism, and baptism of blood is mentioned nowhere.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Dogmatic Council Of Vienne Contradicts “Three Baptisms”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/19-the-dogmatic-council-of-vienne-contradicts-three-baptisms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/19-the-dogmatic-council-of-vienne-contradicts-three-baptisms/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;It would have been interesting to see, however, what St. Thomas would have said if he had lived until the dogmatic Council of Vienne in 1311. St. Thomas died in 1274, 37 years before the Council. The Council of Vienne infallibly defined as a dogma that there is only one baptism that must be confessed by all Catholics, and that the one baptism is water baptism.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Forty Martyrs Of Sebaste &amp; Saint Emerentiana</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/05-forty-martyrs-of-sebaste-saint-emerentiana/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/05-forty-martyrs-of-sebaste-saint-emerentiana/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;An example of how the baptism of blood advocates err in this matter is their assertion that the fortieth martyr of Sebaste was unbaptized. They say that he was unbaptized, but that he joined himself with the other thirty-nine martyrs and froze to death for Christ on the lake. The fact is that there is no proof that the fortieth martyr of Sebaste was unbaptized, whose identity is unknown.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Latin Text of the Oldest Surviving Papal Decree Rejects “Baptism of</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/15-latin-text-oldest-surviving-papal-decree-rejects-baptism-desire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/15-latin-text-oldest-surviving-papal-decree-rejects-baptism-desire/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;THE OLDEST SURVIVING PAPAL DECREE REFUTES ‘BAPTISM OF DESIRE’&#xA;In AD 385 Pope St. Siricius issued a decree to Himerius.&amp;nbsp; This document is frequently called a Letter to Himerius.&amp;nbsp; However, it was actually an authoritative decree in which Pope St. Siricius uses his apostolic authority, promulgates laws, and declares that his decree is to be circulated to, and observed by, all the priests and bishops of the Catholic Church.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Theory of Baptism of Blood - A Tradition of Man</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/02-baptism-of-blood-a-tradition-of-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/02-baptism-of-blood-a-tradition-of-man/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;A small number of the fathers – approximately 8 out of a total of hundreds – are quoted in favor of what is called “baptism of blood,” the idea that a catechumen (that is, one preparing to receive Catholic Baptism) who shed his blood for Christ could be saved without having received Baptism. It is crucial to note at the beginning that none of the fathers considered anyone but a catechumen as a possible exception to receiving the Sacrament of Baptism; they would all condemn and reject as heretical and foreign to the teaching of Christ the modern heresy of “invincible ignorance” saving those who die as non-Catholics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Theory of Baptism of Desire – a tradition of man</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/09-baptism-of-desire-tradition-of-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/09-baptism-of-desire-tradition-of-man/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Those who have been brainwashed by apologists for the theory of baptism of desire may be surprised to learn that of all the fathers of the Church, only 1 can even be brought forward by baptism of desire advocates as having taught the concept. That’s correct, only one, St. Augustine. The baptism of desire advocates will make a feeble attempt to bring forward a second father, St.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two Of The Earliest Statements On Baptism Of Blood</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/03-earliest-statements-on-baptism-of-blood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/03-earliest-statements-on-baptism-of-blood/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Out of the few fathers that can be quoted in favor of baptism of blood being a possible replacement to actual Baptism, two of the very earliest statements supporting the idea come from St. Cyprian and Tertullian.&#xA;St. Cyprian, To Jubaianus (254): “Catechumens who suffer martyrdom before they have received Baptism with water are not deprived of the Sacrament of Baptism.&amp;nbsp; Rather, they are baptized with the most glorious and greatest Baptism of Blood…”[1]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unbaptized Saints?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/04-unbaptized-saints/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/18-heresy-baptism-of-desire-and-blood/04-unbaptized-saints/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;One of the biggest objections from baptism of desire/blood advocates is the claim that the Catholic Church recognizes saints who never received the Sacrament of Baptism. The answer to this is that the Catholic Church has never recognized that there are saints in heaven who were not baptized. Some historians have written accounts of the lives of certain saints in which these saints died without baptism of water – by “baptism of blood”; but the assertions of these historians prove nothing.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
