<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chapter 10 on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</title>
    <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/10/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chapter 10 on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 05:01:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/10/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The activity of the Holy Spirit</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/10/05-activity-of-the-holy-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 05:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/10/05-activity-of-the-holy-spirit/</guid>
      <description>677 Text: Let them pay attention to what they must desire above all else: to have the Spirit of the Lord and Its holy activity, to pray always to Him with a pure heart, to have humility and patience in persecution and infirmity, and to love those who persecute, rebuke, and find fault with us, because the Lord says: “Love your enemies and pray for those who persecute and calumniate you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The study of wisdom</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/10/04-study-of-wisdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 04:58:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/10/04-study-of-wisdom/</guid>
      <description>676 Text: Let those who are illiterate not be anxious to learn.&#xA;Mature Brother – Saint Francis knew how much misfortune and damage would be caused to regular observance by learning and study, through ambition and prestige within the Order and outside it, through the extinguishing of prayer and devotion, through poverty being harmed by purchasing costly and superfluous books and having recourse to money, through riding horses, by the destruction of an observant lifestyle, and countless evils, which we have experienced in days gone by and at present.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Observing the Rule Spiritually</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/10/03-observing-the-rule-spiritualy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 04:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/10/03-observing-the-rule-spiritualy/</guid>
      <description>670 Text: Wherever the brothers may be who know and feel they cannot observe the Rule spiritually, they can and should have recourse to their ministers.&#xA;Mature Brother – Note that when it says “they should” [124v], it commands those who cannot observe the Rule spiritually to have recourse to their ministers. When it says “they can,” it means that they are not to be obstructed and thus it commands the other brothers not to impede them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concerning Sacramental Confession</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/10/02-sacramental-confession/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 04:44:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/10/02-sacramental-confession/</guid>
      <description>Scrupulous Brother. – If a brother recognizes that he is weak and knows that he cannot confess without damaging his soul, is he obliged to obey when commanded?&#xA;Mature Brother. – The Four Masters and the Pisan say that when the superior knows this, he may not command the subject, and the subject is not obliged to obey, just as in other matters which are against his soul and the Rule.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portrait of the “minister and servant” of the brothers</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/10/01-minister-and-servant-of-the-brothers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 03:54:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/10/01-minister-and-servant-of-the-brothers/</guid>
      <description>Text: Let the brothers who are the ministers and servants of the others visit and admonish their brothers and humbly and charitably correct them, not commanding them anything that is against their soul and our Rule. […]&#xA;Scrupulous Brother. – Should a brother who wishes to live without danger accept being Minister?&#xA;Mature Brother. – I say that as far as he can he should avoid that office and other offices.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
