<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Vatican II Revolution (1962-1965) on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</title>
    <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/constitutions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Vatican II Revolution (1962-1965) on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:15 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/constitutions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ad Gentes – Vatican II’s Decree on Missionary Activity</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/constitutions/05-ad-gentes-missionary-activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/constitutions/05-ad-gentes-missionary-activity/</guid>
      <description>Not surprisingly, we also find heresy in Vatican II’s Decree on Missionary Activity.&#xA;Vatican II document, Ad Gentes # 6: “For although the Church possesses totally and fully the means of salvation, it neither always nor at once puts or can put them all into operation, but is subject to beginnings and stages in the activity by which it strives to bring God’s plan into effect. Indeed, at times, after a successful start and advance, it has to grieve at another reverse, or at least it halts in a certain state of semi-fulfillment and insufficiency.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dignitatis Humanae – Vatican II’s Declaration on Religious liberty</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/constitutions/04-dignitatis-humanae-declaration-on-religious-liberty/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/constitutions/04-dignitatis-humanae-declaration-on-religious-liberty/</guid>
      <description>Vatican II’s Declaration on Religious Liberty was without question the most notorious of all the documents of Vatican II. In order to understand why Vatican II’s teaching on religious liberty is heretical one must understand the Catholic Church’s infallible teaching on the issue.&#xA;It’s a dogma of the Catholic Church that States have a right, and indeed a duty, to prevent the members of false religions from publicly propagating and practicing their false faiths.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaudium et Spes – Vatican II’s Constitution on the Church in the Modern World</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/constitutions/07-constitution-on-the-church-in-the-modern-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/constitutions/07-constitution-on-the-church-in-the-modern-world/</guid>
      <description>Vatican II document, Gaudium et Spes # 22: “For by His incarnation the Son of God united Himself in some way with every human being. He labored with human hands, thought with a human mind, acted with a human will, and loved with a human heart.”[105]&#xA;One of the most frequently repeated heresies of the Vatican II sect is the idea that, by His Incarnation, Christ united Himself with each man.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lumen Gentium – Vatican II’s Constitution on the Church</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/constitutions/03-lumen-gentium-constitution-on-the-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/constitutions/03-lumen-gentium-constitution-on-the-church/</guid>
      <description>Lumen Gentium, Vatican II’s constitution on the Church, became famous (or rather, notorious) for its heretical teaching of collegiality. This is the idea that the bishops, taken as a whole, also possess supreme authority in the Catholic Church.&#xA;Vatican II document, Lumen Gentium # 22: “However, the order of Bishops, which succeeds the college of apostles in teaching authority and pastoral government, and indeed in which the apostolic body continues to exist without interruption, is also the subject of supreme and full power over the universal Church, provided it remains united with its head …”[45] We see that Lumen Gentium explicitly teaches that the College of Bishops possesses supreme and full power over the universal Church.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nostra Aetate – Vatican II’s Decree on Non-Christian Religions</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/constitutions/06-nostra-aetate-non-christian-religions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/constitutions/06-nostra-aetate-non-christian-religions/</guid>
      <description>Vatican II document, Nostra aetate # 3: “The Church also looks upon Muslims with respect. They worship the one God living and subsistent, merciful and almighty, creator of heaven and earth, who has spoken to humanity and to whose decrees, even the hidden ones, they seek to submit themselves wholeheartedly, just as Abraham, to whom the Islamic faith readily relates itself, submitted to God… Hence they have regard for the moral life and worship God in prayer, almsgiving and fasting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orientalium ecclesiarum – Vatican II’s Decree on Eastern Catholic Churches</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/constitutions/02-orientalium-ecclesiarum-eastern-catholic-churches/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/constitutions/02-orientalium-ecclesiarum-eastern-catholic-churches/</guid>
      <description>The Vatican II Decree Orientalium ecclesiarum deals with eastern Catholic churches. It also deals with the Eastern Schismatic sects, the so-called “Orthodox” non-Catholic churches. In dealing with the so-called Orthodox in # 27 of this decree, Vatican II provides us with one of its most significant heresies.&#xA;Vatican II document, Orientalium Ecclesiarum # 27: “Given the above-mentioned principles, the sacraments of Penance, Holy Eucharist, and the anointing of the sick may be conferred on eastern Christians who in good faith are separated from the Catholic Church, if they make the request of their own accord and are properly disposed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sacrosanctum Concilium – Vatican II’s Constitution on the Sacred Liturgy</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/constitutions/08-sacrosanctum-concilium-constitution-on-the-sacred-liturgy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/constitutions/08-sacrosanctum-concilium-constitution-on-the-sacred-liturgy/</guid>
      <description>Sacrosanctum Concilium was Vatican II’s constitution on the sacred liturgy. It was responsible for the incredible changes to the Mass and the other sacraments following Vatican II.&#xA;A post-Vatican II “Mass”&#xA;These incredible changes will be covered in more detail in the next section of this book dealing with “The Liturgical Revolution.” What Sacrosanctum Concilium started, Paul VI finished by suppressing the traditional Latin Mass and replacing it with an invalid Protestant service that is referred to as the New Mass or the Novus Ordo Missae (the New Order of the Mass).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unitatis Redintegratio – Vatican II’s Decree on Ecumenism</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/constitutions/01-unitatis-redintegratio-ecumenism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/constitutions/01-unitatis-redintegratio-ecumenism/</guid>
      <description>Vatican II document, Unitatis Redintegratio # 1: “Yet almost all, though in different ways, long for the one visible Church of God, that truly universal Church whose mission is to convert the whole world to the gospel, so that the world may be saved, to the glory of God.”[6]&#xA;At the very beginning of its Decree on Ecumenism, Vatican II teaches that almost everyone longs for a truly universal Church, whose mission is to convert the world to the Gospel.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
