<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Father Feeney on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</title>
    <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/26-father-feeney/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Father Feeney on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/26-father-feeney/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Heresy before Vatican II</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/26-father-feeney/03-heresy-before-vatican-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/26-father-feeney/03-heresy-before-vatican-ii/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;To fully appreciate the Father Feeney controversy one must understand that the denial of the Faith that Father Feeney was combating was well in place in the years before Vatican II. Most people considering themselves to be “traditional Catholics” have the false impression that, “if we could only go back to what people believed in the 1950’s, everything would be fine.” No, it wouldn’t.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mystici Corporis</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/26-father-feeney/04-mystici-corporis-christi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/26-father-feeney/04-mystici-corporis-christi/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Some have the false impression that the horrific pre-Vatican II heresy, which was catalogued above, was also taught by Pope Pius XII in his encyclical Mystici Corporis. This is not true. The passage that the heretics love to quote from Mystici Corporis is weak, but not heretical. It is accurately translated as follows:&#xA;Pope Pius XII, Mystici Corporis, June 29, 1943, Speaking of non-Catholics: “[We wish] every one of them to co-operate generously and willingly with the inward impulses of divine grace and to take care to extricate themselves from that condition in which they cannot be secure about their own eternal salvation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pope Pius XII, Father Feeney and the dogma</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/26-father-feeney/05-pope-pius-xii-father-feeney-the-dogma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/26-father-feeney/05-pope-pius-xii-father-feeney-the-dogma/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;One of the reasons that the heretical and deadly Protocol 122/49 gained such momentum in the minds of so many bishops and priests, and was literally able to wipe out belief in the dogma (that those who die as non-Catholics are lost) in almost the entire Catholic world, was because they thought that it had at least the tacit approval of Pope Pius XII.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protocol 122/49 (Suprema haec sacra)</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/26-father-feeney/02-protocol-122-49-suprema-haec-sacra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/26-father-feeney/02-protocol-122-49-suprema-haec-sacra/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;About four months after the silencing of Fr. Feeney in April by Richard Cushing, the apostate Archbishop of Boston, the Holy Office issued a document on August 8, 1949. Actually, the document was a letter addressed to Bishop Cushing, and signed by Cardinal Marchetti-Selvaggiani, known to most as Protocol No. 122/49. It is also called Suprema haec sacra and the Marchetti-Selvaggiani letter. It is one of the most crucial documents in regard to the modern apostasy from the faith.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Case of Father Feeney</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/26-father-feeney/01-the-case-of-father-feeney/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/26-father-feeney/01-the-case-of-father-feeney/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Heretics and modernists resist the truth, just as they resist Him who is the Truth (Jn. 14:6). And because they resist the truth they resist facts, because facts report truth without any error. One of the facts that the modernists and heretics resist most of all is the fact that the Catholic Church has infallibly taught that Outside the Catholic Church There is No Salvation and that John 3:5 is to be taken as it is written and that the Sacrament of Baptism is necessary for salvation (Trent, Sess.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Heretics Testify</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/26-father-feeney/07-the-heretics-testify/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/26-father-feeney/07-the-heretics-testify/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;In the foregoing sections, I have traced out the history of the Fr. Feeney controversy in the late 1940’s and 1950’s, which was preceded by an apostasy from the dogma Outside the Church There is No Salvation which began in the 19th century – on the heels of misinterpreted and fallible statements of Pope Pius IX on “invincible ignorance” and the explosion of the false doctrine of “baptism of desire.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Verdict is in: Boston Leads the Way in a Massive Priestly Scandal that Rocks the Nation</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/26-father-feeney/06-sexual-scandal-boston/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/26-father-feeney/06-sexual-scandal-boston/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Novus Ordo Priest Fr. Mark S. Massa, “S.J.”, Catholics and American Culture, p. 31, DESCRIBING WHEN THE CONTROVERSY ERUPTED IN BOSTON OVER THE DOGMA, OUTSIDE THE CHURCH THERE IS NO SALVATION: “The Boston Heresy Case erupted into public view during Holy Week 1949. The firings of Feeney’s disciples from Boston College made front-page news all over the Northeast: the New York Times began a series on Feeney and his group, and Newsweek, Life, and Time magazines all featured stories on the Boston ‘troubles.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
