<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sacraments on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</title>
    <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/sacraments/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sacraments on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 13:23:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://eens-en.netlify.app/sacraments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>E-exchanges on the topic of receiving sacraments (2008)</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/sacraments/e-exchanges-on-the-topic-of-receiving-sacraments-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 13:23:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/sacraments/e-exchanges-on-the-topic-of-receiving-sacraments-2008/</guid>
      <description>Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;The Question of whether one may receive Sacraments in these difficult timesDecember 18, 2015By Bro. Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Originally written in 2008&#xA;Please See This File: Where to Receive SacramentsINTRO: Our website demonstrates that a Catholic cannot attend the New Mass, of course. Our website also demonstrates the unfortunate fact that almost all of the priests who are validly ordained and celebrating a traditional Mass today (whether Roman Rite or Eastern Rite) hold heretical views.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On St. Hermenegild and Communion from heretics</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/sacraments/on-st-hermenegild-and-communion-from-heretics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 11:25:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/sacraments/on-st-hermenegild-and-communion-from-heretics/</guid>
      <description>Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;St. Hermenegild was a 6th century martyr who was put to death for refusing to receive Holy Communion from his father’s Arian priest:&#xA;“During Eastertime the Arian father sent to his son a bishop of his sect, offering to receive him into his favor if he would receive Holy Communion from the hands of that prelate. St. Hermenegild refused. The father, enraged, sent soldiers to put him to death.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where To Receive Sacraments</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/sacraments/where-to-receive-sacraments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 11:21:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/sacraments/where-to-receive-sacraments/</guid>
      <description>Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;THE QUESTION OF WHERE TO RECEIVE SACRAMENTS IN OUR TIME QUICK INTRODUCTION AND UPDATE ON THE CURRENT SITUATION&#xA;The Vatican II sect under Antipope Francis is becoming more notorious (and basically openly Protestant) by the day. In fact, it looks poised to openly repudiate Catholic teaching against divorce and remarriage. Moreover, the “canonization” of Antipope John Paul II is a major development. (The Vatican II sect will celebrate Antipope John Paul II’s “feast day” on Oct.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
