<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Bible proves Catholicism on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</title>
    <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Bible proves Catholicism on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>25,000 Different Non-Catholic Denominations – Doctrinal Chaos Is The Bad</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/11-25000-protestant-denominations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/11-25000-protestant-denominations/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;2 Peter 2:1- “But there were also false prophets among the people, even as there shall be among you lying teachers, who shall bring in sects of perdition, and deny the Lord who bought them: bringing upon themselves swift destruction.”&#xA;Following Martin Luther’s excommunication from the Catholic Church in 1520, which marked the beginning of the Protestant movement, over 20,000 different denominations have been created in about 500 years.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Did St. Paul Really Rebuke St. Peter In Galatians 2?</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/13-st-paul-peter-galatians-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/13-st-paul-peter-galatians-2/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Old Is Your Church?</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/12-how-old-is-your-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/12-how-old-is-your-church/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;If you are a Lutheran, your religion was founded by Martin Luther, an ex-monk of the Catholic Church, in approximately 1520.&#xA;If you belong to the Church of England, your religion was founded by King Henry VIII (an ex-Catholic) in the year 1534.&amp;nbsp; Henry VIII decided to create his own church when Pope Clement VII would not grant him a divorce with the right to remarry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jesus is God according to the Bible</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/18-jesus-is-god-bible/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/18-jesus-is-god-bible/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Could you please explain a couple of things for me. Where in the bible does it say that Jesus is God in a human form. Everywhere I look it says Jesus is the son of God... Thank you for your time I look forward to your reply.&#xA;Gary&#xA;The “Jehovah’s Witnesses” and the Unitarians deny that Jesus Christ is God. But there are many passages in the Bible which show that Jesus is God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Justification by Faith Alone and Eternal Security Refuted by the Bible</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/04-faith-alone-refuted-by-the-bible/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/04-faith-alone-refuted-by-the-bible/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Must-See Documentary: Protestantism’s Big Justification Lie (video)&#xA;The overwhelming majority of Protestants believe that the Bible teaches that people are justified (put into a state in which they will be saved) by faith alone in Jesus – i.e., apart from a consideration of their actions, deeds or sins. Most of them also believe in “once saved always saved” or eternal security: that a man who believes in Jesus cannot lose his eternal salvation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mary: Mother Of God &amp; Ark Of The New Covenant - Absolute Proof!</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/15-mary-mother-of-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/15-mary-mother-of-god/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proof for Catholicism in St. Justin Martyr&#39;s First Apology</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/16-proof-for-catholicism-in-st-justin-martyrs-first-apology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/16-proof-for-catholicism-in-st-justin-martyrs-first-apology/</guid>
      <description>Source: vaticancatholic.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refuting the Protestant rejection of the Catholic and the Bible’s teaching</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/17-bible-celibacy-saint-paul/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/17-bible-celibacy-saint-paul/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;“The Catholic Church murdered 10s of thousand of non-Catholic [sic] in its early years. Nowhere does the scripture disallow ministers or priests to marry. By this very rule it promotes the priests to be a battery of PEDIFILES [sic]…” Hayden, Waco, Tx.&#xA;Since this is a somewhat common sentiment among Protestants, it is appropriate to make this unbiblical lie the Heresy of the Week.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Facts about Martin Luther, The Originator of Protestant</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/10-martin-luther/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/10-martin-luther/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Protestantism originated with Martin Luther (1483-1546), an ex-Catholic.&amp;nbsp; Even though Protestants would contend that they follow “true biblical Christianity,” and not a man, they are inclined to defend Martin Luther.&amp;nbsp; This is because Martin Luther was the first identifiable spokesman for their version of “Christianity.”&amp;nbsp; Prior to his separation from the Catholic Church in 1520, there was no public defender of what we now know to be Protestantism, the core doctrines of which are justification by faith alone and Scripture alone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Bible Does Not Teach Sola Scriptura (Scripture Alone)</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/09-bible-and-sola-scriptura-scripture-alone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/09-bible-and-sola-scriptura-scripture-alone/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;2 Thessalonians 2:15- “Therefore, brethren, stand fast, and hold the traditions which ye have been taught, whether by word, or our epistle.”&#xA;According to Protestants, the Bible teaches that Scripture (the written word of God) is the only rule of faith for a Christian. Along with justification by faith alone (sola fide), Scripture alone (sola scriptura) was one of the central tenets of the Protestant “reformation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Bible on Praying to and Venerating Saints of the Catholic Church</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/06-bible-praying-to-saints/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/06-bible-praying-to-saints/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Revelation 8:3-4- “And another angel came and stood at the altar, having a golden censer; and there was given unto him much incense, that he should offer it with the prayers of all saints upon the golden altar which was before the throne.&amp;nbsp; And the smoke of the incense, which came with the prayers of the saints, ascended up before God out of the angel&#39;s hand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Bible Proves The Papacy</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/14-st-peter-acts-15-bible-papacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/14-st-peter-acts-15-bible-papacy/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Bible teaches Baptismal Regeneration and that Baptism is Necessary for</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/07-baptism-bible/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/07-baptism-bible/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;What Millions Of Fake Christians Get Wrong About Ephesians&#xA;Documentary: Protestantism&#39;s Big Justification Lie&#xA;Cornelius, The Gift Of Languages &amp;amp; The Necessity Of Baptism&#xA;Most Protestants today do not believe that baptism regenerates. This includes Baptists, Presbyterians, Pentecostals, most Evangelicals, and many others.&amp;nbsp; They do not believe that baptism removes sin from the soul and places man in a state of justification.&amp;nbsp; Their position is that water baptism should be performed, but that it’s just a sign of initiation, a sign of a conversion or a spiritual rebirth that has already happened.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Bible teaches Confession to a priest</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/05-bible-confession-of-sin-priests/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/05-bible-confession-of-sin-priests/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;The Bible teaches Confession to a priest&amp;nbsp;[23 min. audio] A sincere person cannot deny the facts.&#xA;John 20:22-23- “[Jesus said to them]: Receive ye the Holy Ghost: Whose sins you shall forgive, they are forgiven them; and whose sins you shall retain, they are retained.”&#xA;Many non-Catholics think that confession to a priest is not taught in the Bible.&amp;nbsp; According to them, to be forgiven of even serious sins one must simply believe in Jesus; or at the most, confess those sins directly to God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Bible Teaches Purgatory</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/08-bible-purgatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/08-bible-purgatory/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;There is proof for Purgatory in the Bible.&amp;nbsp; It’s found in 1 Corinthians chapter 3, verse 15.&amp;nbsp; Let’s examine this Biblical proof for Purgatory.&amp;nbsp; I will use the 1611 King James Version of the Bible, a famous Protestant translation.&#xA;1 CORINTHIANS 3:15 IS IRREFUTABLE PROOF FOR PURGATORY&#xA;1 Corinthians 3:11-15- “For other foundation can no man lay than that is laid, which is Jesus Christ.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Bible teaches that Jesus is truly present in the Eucharist</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/01-bible-jesus-present-eucharist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/01-bible-jesus-present-eucharist/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;John 6:53- “Then Jesus said unto them, Verily, verily, I say unto you, Except ye eat the flesh of the Son of man, and drink his blood, ye have no life in you..”&#xA;Protestants do not believe that the Eucharist is the actual body, blood, soul and divinity of Jesus Christ. Catholics believe that after the consecration at Mass, “the Lord Jesus Christ, true God and true man, is truly, really, and substantially contained” in the Eucharist under the appearance of bread and wine (Council of Trent, Decree on the Eucharist).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Bible Teaches that Jesus made St. Peter the First Pope</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/03-bible-papacy-st-peter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/03-bible-papacy-st-peter/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;This is a must-see video. It’s one of the most important videos we have produced. Among other things, it covers a new biblical proof of the Papacy that is of great significance.&#xA;Did St. Paul Really Rebuke St. Peter In Galatians 2? (video)&#xA;Clement and Ignatius - The Early Church recognized the Bishop of Rome as the successor to St. Peter&#39;s authority - Section A of Part 2 [14 min.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Biblical Basis for Praying to Mary and for Catholic Teaching on Mary</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/02-bible-virgin-mary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/bible-proves-catholicism/02-bible-virgin-mary/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;The Blessed Virgin Mary is the mother of Jesus Christ.&amp;nbsp; Contrary to the claims of some, the Catholic Church does not teach and has never taught that Mary is God.&amp;nbsp; That would be heresy.&amp;nbsp; Mary is just a creature, but the greatest of all the human beings ever created by God.&amp;nbsp; Please look at this biblical evidence for the Catholic teachings about Mary, and why it’s so necessary to understand her role and importance.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
