<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Against the Vatican II Sect on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</title>
    <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Against the Vatican II Sect on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:15 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Great Proof Texts For Sedevacantism Show That Francis Is Not The Pope</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/sedevacantism-pope-st-celestine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/sedevacantism-pope-st-celestine/</guid>
      <description>By Bro. Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;This video will cover some very important passages that deal with the Catholic Church’s teaching that someone who holds office in the Church, but preaches notorious heresy, loses authority from the moment that he preaches the heresy, even if no declaration has been made against him.&#xA;St. Robert Bellarmine, De Romano Pontifice, Book 2, Chap. 30: “... a manifestly heretical Pope automatically ceases to be the Pope and the head just as he automatically ceases to be a Christian and a member of the body of the Church, and that for this reason he may be judged and punished by the Church.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Great Apostasy and a counterfeit Church predicted in the New Testament and in Catholic Prophecy</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/great-apostasy-bible/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/great-apostasy-bible/</guid>
      <description>Brother Michael Dimond and Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;John Paul II during a syncretist prayer gathering with various false religious leaders at Assisi in 1986 - This “ecumenical” activity was always condemned by the Catholic Church, and specifically labeled as a complete rejection of the Catholic Faith by Pope Pius XI in 1928. This is a revolution against the Faith – a new Gospel.&#xA;Luke 18:8- “But yet the Son of man, when he cometh, shall he find, think you, faith on earth?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New Rite of Consecration of Bishops</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/new-rite-consecration-bishops/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/new-rite-consecration-bishops/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Michael Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;VIDEO: More Information on the New Rite of Ordination - [17 min.]&#xA;Paul VI also changed the rite for consecrating bishops. This is very significant because groups such as the Fraternity of St. Peter and the Institute of Christ the King (indult groups who offer the traditional Latin Mass) ordain their men in the Traditional Rite of Ordination, but have the ordinations done by “bishops” who were made “bishops” in the New Rite of Episcopal Consecration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New Rite of Ordination is Invalid</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/new-rite-of-ordination-invalid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/new-rite-of-ordination-invalid/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Michael Dimond and Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;VIDEO: More Information on the New Rite of Ordination - [17 min.]&#xA;Michael Davies: “… every prayer in the traditional rite [of Ordination] which stated specifically the essential role of a priest as a man ordained to offer propitiatory sacrifice for the living and dead has been removed [from the New Rite of Paul VI]. In most cases these were the precise prayers removed by the Protestant reformers, or if not precisely the same there are clear parallels.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
