<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Against the Vatican II Sect on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Against the Vatican II Sect on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 19:44:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Heresies of John Paul II, the most traveled man in history and perhaps the most heretical</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/the-heresies-of-john-paul-ii-the-most-traveled-man-in-history-and-perhaps-the-most-heretical/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 19:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/the-heresies-of-john-paul-ii-the-most-traveled-man-in-history-and-perhaps-the-most-heretical/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Michael Dimond and Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;“KING: The pope congratulated your children&#39;s bar mitzvahs?&#xA;”LEVINE: Not only congratulate us, he sent us a menorah.&#xA;”KING: He sent you a menorah?&#xA;”LEVINE: He gave it to us, actually, didn&#39;t send it. Actually gave us a menorah. I think it&#39;s from the 16th century in Prague. It&#39;s the most beautiful menorah. He sent a letter on the occasion of each of my son&#39;s bar mitzvahs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Pope John Paul I and the Illuminati</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/anti-pope-john-paul-i-and-the-illuminati/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 19:43:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/anti-pope-john-paul-i-and-the-illuminati/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Michael Dimond and Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Pope Paul VI - Why He Was Not A Saint (Video Included)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/anti-pope-paul-vi-why-he-was-not-a-saint-video-included/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 19:42:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/anti-pope-paul-vi-why-he-was-not-a-saint-video-included/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Michael Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Paul VI (left) wearing the breast-plate of a Jewish High-Priest, (middle) giving away the Papal Tiara (a symbol of papal authority) and (right) engaging in false ecumenism and a possible masonic handshake with a schismatic leader&#xA;“Saint” Paul VI Photos “Saint” Paul VI’s Photo Gallery&#xA;This file above is a file with some photos of “Saint” Paul VI. There are some very interesting shots, including some new shots of him wearing the breastplate of the ephod.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Pope John XXIII was a Freemason?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/anti-pope-john-xxiii-was-a-freemason/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 19:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/anti-pope-john-xxiii-was-a-freemason/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Michael Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Sacraments: The Changes To The Other Sacraments</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/new-sacraments-the-changes-to-the-other-sacraments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 19:37:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/new-sacraments-the-changes-to-the-other-sacraments/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Michael Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;“These most crafty enemies have filled and inebriated with gall and bitterness the Church, the spouse of the immaculate Lamb, and have laid impious hands on her most sacred possessions. In the Holy Place itself, where has been set up the See of the most holy Peter and the Chair of Truth for the light of the world, they have raised the throne of their abominable impiety, with the iniquitous design that when the Pastor has been struck, the sheep may be scattered.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Catholic Mass Replaced By An Invalid New Mass</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/the-catholic-mass-replaced-by-an-invalid-new-mass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 19:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/the-catholic-mass-replaced-by-an-invalid-new-mass/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Michael Dimond and Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;The Liturgical Revolution - A New Mass “Truly, if one of the devils in C.S. Lewis’ The Screwtape Letters had been entrusted with the ruin of the liturgy he could not have done it better.”[1]&#xA;THE NEW MASS VS. THE TRADITIONAL MASS&#xA;The Traditional Latin Mass, the most holy act of worship of the Roman Rite of the Catholic Church, was codified by Pope St.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New Rite of Ordination is invalid</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/new-rite-of-ordination-is-invalid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 18:35:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/new-rite-of-ordination-is-invalid/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>why the New Mass and New Rite of Ordination are invalide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/why-new-mass-new-rite-of-ordination-are-invalid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 18:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/why-new-mass-new-rite-of-ordination-are-invalid/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Organized Effort To Infiltrate The Catholic Church</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/the-organized-effort-to-infiltrate-the-catholic-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 05:47:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/the-organized-effort-to-infiltrate-the-catholic-church/</guid>
      <description>Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Pope Leo XIII, Dall’Alto (# 2), Oct. 15, 1890: “It is needless now to put the Masonic sects upon their trial. They are already judged; their ends, their means, their doctrines, and their action, are all known with indisputable certainty. Possessed by the spirit of Satan, whose instrument they are, they burn like him with a deadly and implacable hatred of Jesus Christ and of His work; and they endeavor by every means to overthrow and fetter it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Great Western Schism (1378-1417)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/the-great-western-schism-1378-1417/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 05:41:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/the-great-western-schism-1378-1417/</guid>
      <description>Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;The Great Western Schism (1378-1417) and what it teaches us about the post-Vatican II apostasy [PDF] -Massive confusion, multiple antipopes, antipopes in Rome, an antipope recognized by all the cardinals; The Great Western Schism proves that a line of antipopes at the heart of the post-Vatican II crisis is absolutely possible-&#xA;The Breakdown of the Great Western Schism Antipopes&#xA;The Popes&#xA;Urban VI (1378-1389)&#xA;↓&#xA;Boniface IX (1389-1404)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Complete List Of Antipopes In History</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/a-complete-list-of-antipopes-in-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 05:39:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/a-complete-list-of-antipopes-in-history/</guid>
      <description>Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;To understand what God might allow to transpire in the final days, we must understand Catholic teaching on the Papacy and look at some examples in Church history of things that God has allowed to occur with regard to the Papacy.&amp;nbsp; It’s a fact of history, Scripture and tradition that Our Lord Jesus Christ founded His universal Church (the Catholic Church) upon St. Peter.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&#xA;Matthew 16:18-19-“And I say to thee: That thou are Peter: and upon this rock I will build my Church, and the gates of hell shall not prevail against it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Debate: does Vatican II teach that non-Catholics may lawfully receive Holy Communion?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/vatican-ii-teaches-communion-for-non-catholics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 05:34:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/vatican-ii-teaches-communion-for-non-catholics/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Are Now Living Through The Third Secret of Fatima!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/we-are-now-living-through-the-third-secret-of-fatima/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 05:32:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/we-are-now-living-through-the-third-secret-of-fatima/</guid>
      <description>Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Fr. Mario Luigi Ciappi, papal theologian to Pope Pius XII: “In the Third Secret [of Fatima] it is foretold, among other things, that the great apostasy in the Church will begin at the top.”[1]&#xA;The message and miracle of Our Lady of Fatima in 1917 is one of the greatest events in the history of the Catholic Church. Since the miracle at Fatima, which occurred on Oct. 13, 1917, was predicted to take place in advance, and was fulfilled in the presence of almost 100,000 people, it’s probably the greatest miracle in Catholic history outside the Resurrection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Truth about What Really Happened to the Catholic Church after Vatican II Audio Program</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/what-happened-to-catholic-church-after-vatican-ii-audio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 05:32:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/what-happened-to-catholic-church-after-vatican-ii-audio/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pope Leo XIII’s Original Prayer to St. Michael – a Prophecy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/pope-leo-xiiis-original-prayer-to-st-michael-a-prophecy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 05:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/pope-leo-xiiis-original-prayer-to-st-michael-a-prophecy/</guid>
      <description>Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Pope Leo XIII’s Prayer to St. Michael the Archangel is prophetic.&amp;nbsp; Composed over 100 years ago, and then suppressed, Pope Leo XIII’s original Prayer to St. Michael is one of the most interesting and controversial prayers relating to the present situation in which the true Catholic Church finds itself.&amp;nbsp; On September 25, 1888, following his morning Mass, Pope Leo XIII became traumatized to the point that he collapsed.&amp;nbsp; Those in attendance thought that he was dead.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glossary of Terms and Principles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/glossary-of-terms-and-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 05:25:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/glossary-of-terms-and-principles/</guid>
      <description>Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;-This glossary of terms and principles will hopefully provide a quick aid to those unfamiliar with some of the phrases, topics or principles that are frequently discussed in this book.&amp;nbsp; Since we feel it is more beneficial, this glossary has been arranged topically rather than alphabetically.-&#xA;Papacy – the office of a pope, the successor of St. Peter, which was founded by Jesus Christ (Mt. 16:18-20; John 21:15-17) upon St.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vatican II: Council of Apostasy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/vatican-ii-council-of-apostasy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 05:17:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/vatican-ii-council-of-apostasy/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vatican II is a new religion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/vatican-ii-is-a-new-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 05:12:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/vatican-ii-is-a-new-religion/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: endtimes.video&#xA;There are many heresies in Vatican II. This article will focus on one that’s very widespread and quite visible in the Vatican II Sect. (The video linked above contains abundant visual evidence for these points). As our material proves, the Vatican II Sect is not the Catholic Church but the prophesied end-times Counter Church. In number 8 of Vatican II’s decree on ecumenism, we read:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vatican II’s Intercommunion Heresy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/vatican-ii-intercommunion-heresy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 05:06:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/vatican-ii-intercommunion-heresy/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Great Apostasy and a counterfeit Church predicted in the New Testament and in Catholic Prophecy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/great-apostasy-bible/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/great-apostasy-bible/</guid>
      <description>Brother Michael Dimond and Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;John Paul II during a syncretist prayer gathering with various false religious leaders at Assisi in 1986 - This “ecumenical” activity was always condemned by the Catholic Church, and specifically labeled as a complete rejection of the Catholic Faith by Pope Pius XI in 1928. This is a revolution against the Faith – a new Gospel.&#xA;Luke 18:8- “But yet the Son of man, when he cometh, shall he find, think you, faith on earth?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New Rite of Consecration of Bishops</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/new-rite-consecration-bishops/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/new-rite-consecration-bishops/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Michael Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Paul VI also changed the rite for consecrating bishops. This is very significant because groups such as the Fraternity of St. Peter and the Institute of Christ the King (indult groups who offer the traditional Latin Mass) ordain their men in the Traditional Rite of Ordination, but have the ordinations done by “bishops” who were made “bishops” in the New Rite of Episcopal Consecration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New Rite of Ordination is Invalid</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/new-rite-of-ordination-invalid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-vatican-ii/new-rite-of-ordination-invalid/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Michael Dimond and Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Michael Davies: “… every prayer in the traditional rite [of Ordination] which stated specifically the essential role of a priest as a man ordained to offer propitiatory sacrifice for the living and dead has been removed [from the New Rite of Paul VI]. In most cases these were the precise prayers removed by the Protestant reformers, or if not precisely the same there are clear parallels.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
