<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Against the SSPV group on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</title>
    <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-sspv/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Against the SSPV group on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 12:43:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-sspv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Who is Bishop Donald Sanborn?</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-sspv/who-is-bishop-donald-sanborn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 12:43:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-sspv/who-is-bishop-donald-sanborn/</guid>
      <description>Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Bishop Donald Sanborn is a “traditionalist” bishop who attacks those who don’t believe in &#39;baptism of desire&#39;. In addition to attacking Catholic teaching on baptism, Donald Sanborn believes that souls can be saved in false religions. He thus rejects the dogma Outside the Church There is No Salvation as it has been defined.&#xA;Bishop Donald Sanborn, Sacerdotium V, p. 24: “Wojtyla’s ecclesiology goes a step beyond Vatican II, a little step for man, but a great step for apostasy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Sanborn, Big Pharma</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-sspv/donald-sanborn-big-pharma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 12:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-sspv/donald-sanborn-big-pharma/</guid>
      <description>Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;MHFM: False traditionalist (and completely independent) Bishop Donald Sanborn, who heretically believes that souls can be saved in false religions, also thinks that you can trust Big Pharma on vaccines! In light of available facts, his position exposes his PROFOUND BLINDNESS and bad judgment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exchanges On The Stupidity Of Sanborn’s Position</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-sspv/exchanges-on-the-stupidity-of-sanborns-position/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 12:42:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-sspv/exchanges-on-the-stupidity-of-sanborns-position/</guid>
      <description>Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Exchanges On The Stupidity Of Sanborn’s Position&#xA;Sanborn And Others Are Totally Wrong On Manifest Heresy – New Evidence From Pope Martin V&#xA;Brothers, I disagree with the CT [Cassiciacum Thesis], but I don&#39;t believe… Sanborn believes Bergoglio is Catholic anything. Where are you getting that he thinks he is a &#34;true Catholic cardinal&#34;?&#xA;D&#xA;MHFM You are incorrect. Their position that the V2 Sect&#39;s &#39;cardinals&#39; are true cardinals is a key aspect of &#39;the Thesis&#39;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hypocrisy Of Donald Sanborn&#39;s Group</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-sspv/the-hypocrisy-of-donald-sanborns-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 12:41:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-sspv/the-hypocrisy-of-donald-sanborns-group/</guid>
      <description>Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;MHFM: It’s remarkable to see certain blind supporters of Donald Sanborn’s pseudo-sedevacantist group denounce the ‘Recognize and Resist’ position, while they fail to realize that Sanborn’s group holds the ‘Recognize and Resist’ position. Yes, Sanborn’s group holds the Cassiciacum Thesis, according to which all the Novus Ordo ‘cardinals’ (including Jorge Bergoglio) are true Catholic cardinals! Yet they resist communion with their ‘Catholic cardinals’, they reject the ‘pope’ (i.e. Bergoglio) who is recognized by their ‘cardinals’, and they resist the special privileges that Catholic cardinals enjoy according to canon 239 of the 1917 Code of Canon Law (such as the ability to preach anywhere).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bishop Sanborn And John Salza Are Totally Wrong On Manifest Heresy - New Evidence From Pope Martin V</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-sspv/bishop-sanborn-and-john-salza-are-totally-wrong-on-manifest-heresy-new-evidence-from-pope-martin-v/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-sspv/bishop-sanborn-and-john-salza-are-totally-wrong-on-manifest-heresy-new-evidence-from-pope-martin-v/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The SSPV</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-sspv/the-sspv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-sspv/the-sspv/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Society Of St. Pius V</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-sspv/sspv-against-water-baptism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-sspv/sspv-against-water-baptism/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;In our previous magazines we have pointed out the unfortunate fact that the priests of the Society of St. Pius V hold to the heresy that non-Catholics can be saved without the Catholic Faith. For instance, they endorsed the following blatantly heretical question and answer in their publication:&#xA;The Society of St. Pius V, The Roman Catholic, Winter, 2005, p. 54: “Q. Do Catholics believe that non-Catholics cannot be saved.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
