<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Baptism is necessary for Salvation on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</title>
    <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/baptism-is-necessary-for-salvation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Baptism is necessary for Salvation on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/baptism-is-necessary-for-salvation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Baptism (John 3:5) Vs. The Eucharist (John 6:53) In Regard To Necessity</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/baptism-is-necessary-for-salvation/bible-john-3-5-and-john-6-53-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/baptism-is-necessary-for-salvation/bible-john-3-5-and-john-6-53-video/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Bro. Peter Dimond&#xA;A false traditionalist priest recently accused us of blatant modernism because we point out a difference in the wording and in the ultimate application of Jesus’ profound statements in John 6, concerning the necessity to receive the Eucharist for salvation, and John 3:5 concerning the necessity to receive the Sacrament of Baptism for salvation. We will quote what he said and then refute it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Baptism of God</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/baptism-is-necessary-for-salvation/the-baptism-of-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/baptism-is-necessary-for-salvation/the-baptism-of-god/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;At the end of Mass in the Roman Rite is recited the Last Gospel. These profound words found in the first chapter of the Gospel of St. John are very powerful, striking the reader by the depths of their wisdom and meaning. It is in these very words that we find a provocative argument against baptism of desire:&#xA;John 1:12-13-“But as many as received Him, to them He gave power to become the sons of God: to them that believe in His name: WHO ARE BORN, NOT OF BLOOD, NOR OF THE WILL OF THE FLESH, NOR OF THE WILL OF MAN, BUT OF GOD.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concerning Those Baptized Validly As Infants By Members Of Non-Catholic Sects</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/baptism-is-necessary-for-salvation/those-baptized-validly-as-infants-by-non-catholics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/baptism-is-necessary-for-salvation/those-baptized-validly-as-infants-by-non-catholics/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;The Catholic Church has always taught that anyone (including a layman or a non-Catholic) can validly baptize if he adheres to proper matter and form and if he has the intention of doing what the Church does.&#xA;Pope Eugene IV, Council of Florence, “Exultate Deo,” 1439: “In case of necessity, however, not only a priest or a deacon, but even a layman or woman, yes even a pagan and a heretic can baptize, so long as he preserves the form of the Church and has the intention of doing what the Church does.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cornelius The Centurion</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/baptism-is-necessary-for-salvation/cornelius-the-centurion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/baptism-is-necessary-for-salvation/cornelius-the-centurion/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION- Acts 10:47 says that Cornelius and his companions received the Holy Ghost.&amp;nbsp; This means that they were justified without Baptism.&#xA;ANSWER- Acts 10:47 does not say that Cornelius and his companions were justified without Baptism.&amp;nbsp; Nothing there says that their sins were remitted or that they were “saved,” a phrase frequently used to describe those who have been justified by Baptism.&amp;nbsp; The context of Acts 10 is dealing with receiving the Holy Ghost by receiving the gift of speaking in tongues, not having one’s sins remitted.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The “Within but Not A Member” Objection of Msgr. Fenton</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/baptism-is-necessary-for-salvation/within-but-not-a-member-fenton/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/baptism-is-necessary-for-salvation/within-but-not-a-member-fenton/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION- In his book The Catholic Church and Salvation, Msgr. Joseph Clifford Fenton points out that, while only the baptized are actual members of the Church, one can be “within” or “inside” the Church without being a member.&amp;nbsp; Thus, the unbaptized can be saved without being members of the Catholic Church because they can still be “inside.”&#xA;&amp;nbsp;Pope Pius XII, Mystici Corporis (# 22), June 29, 1943:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; “Actually only those are to be numbered among the members of the Church who have received the laver of regeneration and profess the true faith.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New Testament is clear that the Sacrament of Baptism is Indispensable for Salvation</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/baptism-is-necessary-for-salvation/new-testament-baptism-necessary-salvation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/baptism-is-necessary-for-salvation/new-testament-baptism-necessary-salvation/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;I have already discussed John 3:5, so I will now look at some of the other New Testament passages which affirm the absolute necessity of the Sacrament of Baptism for salvation.&#xA;Summary: The Great Commission – Matthew 28 And Mark 16 Romans 5 And 6 1 Corinthians 12:13 Galatians 3 – Faith Is Baptism Titus 3:5 – Baptism Saves Us Ephesians 4:5 – One Spirit – One Body – One Faith – One Lord – One Baptism.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sacrament of Baptism is Necessary for Salvation</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/baptism-is-necessary-for-salvation/sacrament-of-baptism-necessary-for-salvation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/baptism-is-necessary-for-salvation/sacrament-of-baptism-necessary-for-salvation/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;To further show that the Sacrament of Baptism is necessary for salvation, I will quote numerous other infallible statements from the Chair of St. Peter.&#xA;Pope Paul III, The Council of Trent, Sess. 7, Can. 5 on the Sacrament of Baptism, ex cathedra: “If anyone says that baptism [the Sacrament] is optional, that is, not necessary for salvation (cf. Jn. 3:5): let him be anathema.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sacrament of Baptism is the only Way into the Church</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/baptism-is-necessary-for-salvation/sacrament-of-baptism-only-way-into-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/baptism-is-necessary-for-salvation/sacrament-of-baptism-only-way-into-church/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;The Catholic Church has always taught that receiving the Sacrament of Baptism is the only way into Christ’s Church, outside of which there is no salvation.&#xA;Pope Julius III, Council of Trent, On the Sacraments of Baptism and Penance, Sess. 14, Chap. 2, ex cathedra: “But in fact this sacrament [Penance] is seen to differ in many respects from baptism. For, apart from the fact that the matter and form, by which the essence of a sacrament is constituted, are totally distinct, there is certainly no doubt that the minister of baptism need not be a judge, since the Church exercises judgment on no one who has not previously entered it by the gate of baptism.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There is only One Baptism, Not Three</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/baptism-is-necessary-for-salvation/only-one-baptism-eph-4-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/baptism-is-necessary-for-salvation/only-one-baptism-eph-4-5/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;It is defined Catholic dogma that there is only one baptism. This is why the dogmatic Nicene Creed, historically professed every Sunday in the Roman Rite, reads: “I confess one baptism for the remission of sins.” And this dogma that there is one baptism for the remission of sins comes from Our Lord and the Apostles. It is affirmed by St. Paul in Ephesians 4:5: “One Lord, one faith, one baptism.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trent’s Teaching on The Necessity of Penance vs. its Teaching on the Necessity of Baptism</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/baptism-is-necessary-for-salvation/trent-necessity-of-penance-vs-baptism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/baptism-is-necessary-for-salvation/trent-necessity-of-penance-vs-baptism/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION- I know that the Council of Trent defines in Canon 5 on the Sacrament of Baptism that the Sacrament of Baptism is necessary for salvation.&amp;nbsp; But the Council of Trent says that the necessity of the Sacrament of Penance is the same as that of Baptism, and that people can be justified without the Sacrament of Penance.&#xA;Pope Paul III, The Council of Trent, canons on the Sacrament of Baptism, canon 5, ex cathedra: “If anyone says that baptism [the Sacrament] is optional, that is, not necessary for salvation (cf.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water is Necessary for Baptism and John 3:5 is literal</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/baptism-is-necessary-for-salvation/water-necessary-for-baptism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/baptism-is-necessary-for-salvation/water-necessary-for-baptism/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;“JESUS ANSWERED: AMEN, AMEN, I SAY TO THEE, UNLESS A MAN BE BORN AGAIN OF WATER AND THE HOLY GHOST, HE CANNOT ENTER INTO THE KINGDOM OF GOD.” (JOHN 3:5)&#xA;The Catholic Church is the guardian and interpreter of the Sacred Scriptures. She alone has been given the power and authority to infallibly determine the true sense of the sacred texts.&#xA;Pope Pius IX, First Vatican Council, Sess.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
