<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Outside the Catholic Church there is absolutely no Salvation on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Outside the Catholic Church there is absolutely no Salvation on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Note to Those Who Believe in Baptism of Desire</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/27-a-note-to-those-who-believe-in-baptism-of-desire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/27-a-note-to-those-who-believe-in-baptism-of-desire/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;In discussing this crucial dogma of the faith, I felt that it was important to address something to those of you who believe in baptism of desire, in order to sum up certain points. First, when the facts are laid on the table, you must admit that baptism of desire has never been infallibly taught. The only two quotations from the infallible Magisterium that you even try to bring forward (Sess.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All True Justice and the Causes of Justification</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/23-all-true-justice-and-the-causes-of-justification/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/23-all-true-justice-and-the-causes-of-justification/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;ALL TRUE JUSTICE MEETS UP WITH THE SACRAMENTS (de fide) In the Foreword to Sess. 7 of the Council of Trent’s Decree on the Sacraments there is a very important statement.&#xA;Pope Paul III, Council of Trent, Sess. 7, Foreword, ex cathedra: “For the completion of the salutary doctrine of Justification… it has seemed fitting to treat of the most holy sacraments of the Church, through which all true justice either begins, or being begun is increased or being lost is restored.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catholics Must Believe and Profess that the Sacramental System as a whole is Necessary for Salvation (de fide)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/24-catholics-sacramental-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/24-catholics-sacramental-system/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Another very important aspect to this issue is the Dogmatic Profession of Faith issued by the Council of Trent and by Vatican Council I. Both councils infallibly declared that the sacramental system as a whole is necessary for salvation, and this truth must be professed and believed by all Catholics and by converts.&#xA;Pope Pius IV, “Iniunctum nobis,” Nov. 13, 1565, ex cathedra: “I also profess that there are truly and properly seven sacraments of the New Law instituted by Jesus Christ our Lord, and necessary for the salvation of mankind, although all are not necessary for each individual…”[1]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conclusion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/30-conclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/30-conclusion/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;In this document I have shown that it is the infallible teaching of the Catholic Church – and therefore the true teaching of Jesus Christ – that only those who die as baptized Catholics can be saved. Anyone who refuses to accept this teaching is not a Catholic. The fact that most of the world refuses to accept this teaching must not get us discouraged.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>St. Isaac Jogues and St. Francis Xavier Against Invincible Ignorance and on the Necessity of Baptism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/25-st-isaac-jogues-st-francis-xavier-vs-invincible-ignorance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/25-st-isaac-jogues-st-francis-xavier-vs-invincible-ignorance/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Summary:&#xA;1. Isaac Jogues against Invincible Ignorance&#xA;2. Francis Xavier against Invincible Ignorance&#xA;3. Isaac Jogues on the Necessity of Water Baptism&#xA;4. Amazing Baptisms&#xA;5. Other Quotes from Jogues and Xavier on Baptism&#xA;In this work on Outside the Catholic Church There is No Salvation and the necessity of the Sacrament of Baptism, I could not leave out a section on the incredible lives of two of the most illustrious missionaries in Church history, St.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Degenerate Result of Heresy against this Dogma</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/28-the-degenerate-result-of-heresy-against-this-dogma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/28-the-degenerate-result-of-heresy-against-this-dogma/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;The heresy that “invincible ignorance” saves those who die as non-Catholics and that non-Catholics can be saved by “baptism of desire” often quickly results in an apostasy from Christ Himself. The famous Irish priest, Fr. Denis Fahey, is a case in point.&#xA;Fr. Denis Fahey, The Kingship of Christ and the Conversion of the Jewish Nation (1953), p. 52: “The Jews, as a nation, are objectively aiming at giving society a direction which is in complete opposition to the order God wants.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baptism of Desire vs. The Universal and Constant teaching of Theologians</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/20-universal-and-constant-teaching-of-theologians/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/20-universal-and-constant-teaching-of-theologians/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Recently, an article was published by Fr. Anthony Cekada called Baptism of Desire and Theological Principles. Fr. Cekada is a “traditionalist” priest who rightly rejects Vatican II but yet holds the heresy common to almost all today: that those who die as non-Catholics can be saved. Fr. Cekada is, therefore, a person who rejects the Catholic dogma that the Catholic Faith is necessary for salvation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Believe Dogma as it was once declared</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/03-believe-dogma-as-once-declared/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/03-believe-dogma-as-once-declared/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;There is only one way to believe dogma: as holy mother Church has once declared.&#xA;This definition of the First Vatican Council is critically important for dogmatic purity, because the primary way the Devil attempts to corrupt Christ’s doctrines is by getting men to recede (move away) from the Church’s dogmas as they were once declared. &amp;nbsp;There is no meaning of a dogma other than what the words themselves state and declare, so the Devil tries to get men to “understand” and “interpret” these words in a way that is different from how holy mother Church has declared them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concerning Those Baptized Validly As Infants By Members Of Non-Catholic Sects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/17-those-baptized-validly-as-infants-by-non-catholics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/17-those-baptized-validly-as-infants-by-non-catholics/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;The Catholic Church has always taught that anyone (including a layman or a non-Catholic) can validly baptize if he adheres to proper matter and form and if he has the intention of doing what the Church does.&#xA;Pope Eugene IV, Council of Florence, “Exultate Deo,” 1439: “In case of necessity, however, not only a priest or a deacon, but even a layman or woman, yes even a pagan and a heretic can baptize, so long as he preserves the form of the Church and has the intention of doing what the Church does.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exultate Deo Also Ends The Debate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/21-exultate-deo-also-ends-the-debate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/21-exultate-deo-also-ends-the-debate/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;I have discussed the teaching of the Council of Florence on Baptism in earlier sections; but, due to the fact that the teaching of Exultate Deo from the Council of Florence excludes the possibility of baptism of desire and baptism of blood, I want to show clearly that it is infallible and cannot be contradicted. Pope Eugene IV, The Council of Florence, “Exultate Deo,” Nov.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Infants Cannot Be Saved Without Baptism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/10-infant-aborted-baptism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/10-infant-aborted-baptism/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;The teaching of the Catholic Church already cited shows that no one can be saved without the Sacrament of Baptism. Obviously, therefore, this means that children and infants also cannot get to Heaven without Baptism because they are conceived in a state of original sin, which cannot be removed without the Sacrament of Baptism. But this truth of the Catholic Church is denied by many people today.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Other Popes on Outside the Church There is No Salvation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/04-other-popes-salvation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/04-other-popes-salvation/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;In addition to the ex cathedra (from the Chair of Peter) proclamations of the popes, a Catholic must also believe what is taught by the Catholic Church as divinely revealed in her Ordinary and Universal Magisterium (Magisterium = the teaching authority of the Church).&#xA;Pope Pius IX, Vatican I, Sess. III, Chap. 3, ex cathedra: “Further, by divine and Catholic faith, all those things must be believed which are contained in the written word of God and in tradition, and those which are proposed by the Church, either in a solemn pronouncement or in her ordinary and universal teaching power, to be believed as divinely revealed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Specific Catholic Teaching Against Judaism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/14-against-judaism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/14-against-judaism/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Jews practice the Old Law and reject the Divinity of Christ and the Trinity. The Church teaches the following about the cessation of the Old Law and about all who continue to observe it:&#xA;Pope Eugene IV, Council of Florence, 1441, ex cathedra:&#xA;“The Holy Roman Church firmly believes, professes and teaches that the matter pertaining to the law of the Old Testament, the Mosaic law, which are divided into ceremonies, sacred rites, sacrifices, and sacraments, because they were established to signify something in the future, although they were suited to the divine worship at that time, after our Lord’s coming had been signified by them, ceased, and the sacraments of the New Testament began; and that whoever, even after the passion, placed hope in these matters of the law and submitted himself to them as necessary for salvation, as if faith in Christ could not save without them, sinned mortally.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Specific Catholic Teaching Against Protestant and Schismatic Sects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/16-against-protestant-and-schismatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/16-against-protestant-and-schismatics/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;The Catholic Church also teaches that those baptized persons who embrace heretical or schismatic sects will lose their souls. Jesus founded His Church upon St. Peter, as we saw already, and declared that whoever does not hear the Church be considered as the heathen and publican (Matthew 18:17). He also commanded His followers to observe “all things whatsoever” He has commanded (Matthew 28:20). The Eastern schismatic sects (such as the “Orthodox”) and the Protestant sects are breakoff movements that have separated from the Catholic Church.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Specific Teaching Against Islam</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/15-against-islam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/15-against-islam/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Pope Eugene IV, Council of Basel, Session 19, Sept. 7, 1434:&#xA;“… there is hope that very many from the abominable sect of Mahomet will be converted to the Catholic faith.”[1]&#xA;Pope Callixtus III, 1455: “I vow to… exalt the true Faith, and to extirpate the diabolical sect of the reprobate and faithless Mahomet [Islam] in the East.”[2]&#xA;The Catholic Church considers Islam an “abominable” and “diabolical” sect.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Subjection To The Roman Pontiff &amp; The Necessity Of Baptism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/07-subject-to-roman-pontiff/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/07-subject-to-roman-pontiff/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;This video will focus on the dogma that one must be subject to the Roman Pontiff to be saved and how this dogma also proves that no one can be saved without the Sacrament of Baptism.&amp;nbsp; In the famous bull Unam Sanctam of 1302, Pope Boniface VIII declared that there is no salvation nor remission of sins outside the Catholic Church.&amp;nbsp; He then solemnly defined:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Athanasian Creed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/13-athanasian-creed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/13-athanasian-creed/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;The Athanasian Creed is one of the most important creeds of the Catholic Faith. It contains a beautiful summary of a Catholic’s belief in the Trinity and the Incarnation, which are the two fundamental dogmas of Christianity. Before the 1971 changes in the Liturgy, the Athanasian Creed, consisting of 40 rhythmic statements, had been used in the Sunday Office for over a thousand years.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Chair of St. Peter on Outside the Catholic Church There is No</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/01-chair-of-peter-outside-the-church-no-salvation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/01-chair-of-peter-outside-the-church-no-salvation/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;The following statements on Outside the Catholic Church There is No Salvation are from the highest teaching authority of the Catholic Church.&amp;nbsp; They are ex cathedra Papal decrees (decrees from the Chair of St. Peter).&amp;nbsp; Therefore, they constitute the teaching given to the Catholic Church by Jesus Christ and the Apostles.&amp;nbsp; Such teachings are unchangeable and are classified as part of the solemn magisterium (the extraordinary teaching authority of the Catholic Church).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Keys of St. Peter and his Unfailing Faith</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/02-keys-st-peter-unfailing-faith/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/02-keys-st-peter-unfailing-faith/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;It is a fact of history, scripture and tradition that Our Lord Jesus Christ founded His universal Church (the Catholic Church) upon St. Peter.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&#xA;Matthew 16:18-19-“And I say to thee: That thou art Peter: and upon this rock I will build my Church, and the gates of hell shall not prevail against it. And I will give to thee the keys of the kingdom of heaven.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The One Church of the Faithful</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/06-the-one-church-of-the-faithful/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/06-the-one-church-of-the-faithful/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Pope Innocent III, Fourth Lateran Council, Constitution 1, 1215, ex cathedra: “THERE IS INDEED ONE UNIVERSAL CHURCH OF THE FAITHFUL, outside of which nobody at all is saved, in which Jesus Christ is both priest and sacrifice.”[1]&#xA;The first dogmatic definition from the Chair of Peter on Outside the Church There is No Salvation (from Pope Innocent III) taught that the Catholic Church is the one Church “of the faithful,” outside of which no one at all is saved.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sacrament of Baptism is Necessary for Salvation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/08-sacrament-of-baptism-necessary-for-salvation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/08-sacrament-of-baptism-necessary-for-salvation/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;To further show that the Sacrament of Baptism is necessary for salvation, I will quote numerous other infallible statements from the Chair of St. Peter.&#xA;Pope Paul III, The Council of Trent, Sess. 7, Can. 5 on the Sacrament of Baptism, ex cathedra: “If anyone says that baptism [the Sacrament] is optional, that is, not necessary for salvation (cf. Jn. 3:5): let him be anathema.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sacrament of Baptism is the only Way into the Church</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/05-sacrament-of-baptism-only-way-into-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/05-sacrament-of-baptism-only-way-into-church/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;The Catholic Church has always taught that receiving the Sacrament of Baptism is the only way into Christ’s Church, outside of which there is no salvation.&#xA;Pope Julius III, Council of Trent, On the Sacraments of Baptism and Penance, Sess. 14, Chap. 2, ex cathedra: “But in fact this sacrament [Penance] is seen to differ in many respects from baptism. For, apart from the fact that the matter and form, by which the essence of a sacrament is constituted, are totally distinct, there is certainly no doubt that the minister of baptism need not be a judge, since the Church exercises judgment on no one who has not previously entered it by the gate of baptism.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There is only One Baptism, Not Three</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/12-only-one-baptism-eph-4-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/12-only-one-baptism-eph-4-5/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;It is defined Catholic dogma that there is only one baptism. This is why the dogmatic Nicene Creed, historically professed every Sunday in the Roman Rite, reads: “I confess one baptism for the remission of sins.” And this dogma that there is one baptism for the remission of sins comes from Our Lord and the Apostles. It is affirmed by St. Paul in Ephesians 4:5: “One Lord, one faith, one baptism.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Those who Die in Original Sin or Mortal Sin descend into Hell</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/11-people-who-die-in-mortal-sin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/11-people-who-die-in-mortal-sin/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;As I have proven above, there is no possible way for children to be freed from original sin other than through the Sacrament of Baptism.&amp;nbsp; This, of course, proves that there is no way for infants to be saved other than through the Sacrament of Baptism.&amp;nbsp; So the following definitions merely affirm what has already been established: no child can possibly enter the kingdom of Heaven without receiving water baptism, but will rather descend into Hell.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water is Necessary for Baptism and John 3:5 is literal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/09-water-necessary-for-baptism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/09-water-necessary-for-baptism/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;“JESUS ANSWERED: AMEN, AMEN, I SAY TO THEE, UNLESS A MAN BE BORN AGAIN OF WATER AND THE HOLY GHOST, HE CANNOT ENTER INTO THE KINGDOM OF GOD.” (JOHN 3:5)&#xA;The Catholic Church is the guardian and interpreter of the Sacred Scriptures. She alone has been given the power and authority to infallibly determine the true sense of the sacred texts.&#xA;Pope Pius IX, First Vatican Council, Sess.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
