<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Against &#34;baptisms&#34; of desire and blood on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-bod-bob/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Against &#34;baptisms&#34; of desire and blood on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-bod-bob/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Can Baptism Of Desire Be Contrary To Dogma When...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-bod-bob/baptism-of-desire-contrary-to-dogma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-bod-bob/baptism-of-desire-contrary-to-dogma/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION- How can baptism of desire be contrary to dogma when a saint such as St. Alphonsus believed in it after the Council of Trent? That would make him a heretic, which is impossible since he is a canonized saint.&#xA;ANSWER- First, the key to heresy is obstinacy/pertinacity. It is a fact that a man (if he is not obstinate) could hold a position that is heretical, such as the idea that Christ only has one will, without being a heretic (unless the man came to depart from the essential belief in the Trinity and Incarnation; in that case, even if he were not obstinate, he would lose the Catholic Faith).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pope Innocent II</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-bod-bob/pope-innocent-ii-baptism-of-desire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-bod-bob/pope-innocent-ii-baptism-of-desire/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION- Pope Innocent II taught that a priest could be saved without the Sacrament of Baptism by his desire for it and his confession of the true faith (Denzinger 388): “To your inquiry we respond thus: We assert without hesitation (on the authority of the holy fathers Augustine and Ambrose) that the priest whom you indicated (in your letter) had died without the water of baptism, because he persevered in the faith of holy mother Church and in the confession of the name of Christ, was freed from original sin and attained the joy of the heavenly fatherland.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pope Innocent III</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-bod-bob/pope-innocent-iii-baptism-of-desire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-bod-bob/pope-innocent-iii-baptism-of-desire/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION-&amp;nbsp; Pope Innocent III taught that a person who baptized himself could be saved by the desire for the Sacrament of Baptism.&#xA;Pope Innocent III, to the Bishop of Metz, Aug. 28, 1206: “We respond that, since there should be a distinction between the one baptizing and the one baptized, as is clearly gathered from the words of the Lord, when he says to the Apostles: ‘Go, baptize all nations in the name etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sess. 7, Can. 4 On The Sacraments</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-bod-bob/sess-7-can-4-on-the-sacraments-trent/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-bod-bob/sess-7-can-4-on-the-sacraments-trent/</guid>
      <description>Actually Refutes Baptism of Desire, as Can Be Seen When Compared with Similar Dogmatic Canons on The Sacraments in General.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>St. Alphonsus’ Blatant Error on ‘Baptism of Desire’</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-bod-bob/st-alphonsus-blatant-error-on-baptism-of-desire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-bod-bob/st-alphonsus-blatant-error-on-baptism-of-desire/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Supporters of ‘baptism of desire’ are fond of quoting St. Alphonsus’ opinion on the issue. In our video, Baptism of Desire Buried (linked below), we carefully discuss it. We not only demonstrate that St. Alphonsus’ explanation of BOD (i.e., ‘baptism of desire’) is riddled with problems, but that it would have to be rejected even by ‘baptism of desire’ supporters. Many supporters of ‘BOD,’ however, didn’t seem to notice or grasp the significance of the point made in the video on that particular issue.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 1917 Code of Canon Law</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-bod-bob/1917-code-of-canon-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-bod-bob/1917-code-of-canon-law/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;John 3:5 Mockers Stumped (1917 Code, Delayed Ensoulment, “Baptism Of Desire”) THE VIDEO ABOVE IS A MUST-SEE VIDEO ON THIS MATTER&#xA;OBJECTION- The 1917 Code of Canon Law gives Christian Burial to unbaptized catechumens and teaches baptism of desire.&#xA;ANSWER- As we’ve pointed out before, the 1917 Code of Canon Law is not infallible. The 1917 Code was definitely not an ex cathedra (from the Chair of Peter) pronouncement because it does not bind the whole Church, but only the Latin Church (not the Eastern Rites), as stipulated in Canon 1 of the 1917 Code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Argument from Silence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-bod-bob/argument-from-silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-bod-bob/argument-from-silence/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION- If it is true that there is no such thing as baptism of desire or baptism of blood, then why didn’t any pope come out and condemn these theories as they were appearing in so many catechisms in the late 1800’s and following?&#xA;ANSWER- Baptism of desire and baptism of blood are shown in various ways to be excluded by the infallible teaching of the Catholic Church.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Argument That Baptism Is Impossible For Some To Receive</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-bod-bob/baptism-not-impossible-to-receive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-bod-bob/baptism-not-impossible-to-receive/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION-&amp;nbsp; Baptism of desire supporters assert that for some people the command to be baptized is simply impossible to fulfill.&#xA;ANSWER- God does not command impossibilities (de fide).&amp;nbsp; Thus, it is not impossible for any man to get baptized.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;Catechism of the Council of Trent, On Baptism, Tan Books, p. 171:&#xA;&#34;Holy writers are unanimous in saying that after the Resurrection of our Lord, WHEN HE GAVE HIS APOSTLES THE COMMAND to go and teach all nations: baptizing them in the name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Ghost, THE LAW OF BAPTISM became obligatory on all who were to be saved.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Catechism of Trent and “Baptism of Desire”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-bod-bob/catechism-of-trent-baptism-of-desire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-bod-bob/catechism-of-trent-baptism-of-desire/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION- The Catechism of the Council of Trent taught that the design and plan of receiving Baptism could avail a person to grace and righteousness, if it is impossible for that person to receive Baptism. That means that “baptism of desire” must be Catholic teaching.&#xA;Catechism of the Council of Trent, “Ordinarily They Are Not Baptized At Once,” p. 179: “But though these things may be thus, nevertheless to this class [or kind] of men [persons], the Church has not been accustomed to give the Sacrament of Baptism at once, but has arranged that it should be deferred to a fixed time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Council Of Trent Did Not Teach &#34;Baptism Of Desire&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-bod-bob/council-of-trent-did-not-teach-baptism-of-desire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-bod-bob/council-of-trent-did-not-teach-baptism-of-desire/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Some people think that baptism of desire is taught by the Council of Trent in Sess. 6, Chap 4 on justification. This video will show why they are wrong. It will also cover some very important new points and quotes. The passage says:&#xA;Pope Paul III, Council of Trent, Sess. 6, Chap. 4: “In these words there is conveyed a description of the justification of the impious, how there is a transition from that state in which a person is born as a child of the first Adam to the state of grace and of adoption as sons of God through the second Adam, Jesus Christ our savior; indeed, this transition, after the Gospel has been promulgated, CANNOT TAKE PLACE WITHOUT the laver of regeneration or a desire for it, AS IT IS WRITTEN: Unless a man is born again of water and the Holy Spirit, he cannot enter the kingdom of God (John 3:5).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Errors of Michael Du Bay</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-bod-bob/errors-of-michael-du-bay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-bod-bob/errors-of-michael-du-bay/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION- Wasn’t the idea that catechumens cannot have the remission of sins condemned in the Errors of Michael Du Bay?&#xA;ANSWER- No!&amp;nbsp; And the fact that certain baptism of desire advocates obstinately attempt to quote the Errors of Michael Du Bay in favor of baptism of desire simply shows: 1) their dishonesty; and 2) their lack of evidence for “baptism of desire.”&#xA;Errors of Michael Du Bay, Condemned by St.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Good Thief and The Holy Innocents</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-bod-bob/good-thief-holy-innocents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/against-bod-bob/good-thief-holy-innocents/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;ANSWER- This was addressed already in the section on St. Augustine, but it will be repeated here for those who may be looking for it in this section of “Other Objections.” The Good Thief cannot be used as an example of baptism of blood primarily because the Good Thief died under the Old Law, not the New Law; he died before the Law of Baptism was instituted by Jesus Christ after the Resurrection.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
