<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Against the &#34;Saved by invincible ignorance&#34; heresy on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</title>
    <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-invincible-ignorance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Against the &#34;Saved by invincible ignorance&#34; heresy on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-invincible-ignorance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Invincible Ignorance Becomes A Destructive Heresy,</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-invincible-ignorance/invincible-ignorance-destructive-heresy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-invincible-ignorance/invincible-ignorance-destructive-heresy/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;The heresy that non-Catholics can be saved by “invincible ignorance” wasn’t really a problem before the year 1800, since the teaching of Catholic Tradition that no one can be saved who is ignorant of the Gospel was quite clear and maintained by most. But thanks to the growing modernism in the 1850’s, combined with the liberals’ hijacking of Pope Pius IX’s weak statements, the heretical theory of salvation for the invincibly ignorant exploded and became the belief of many priests in the latter half of the 19th century and the first half of the 20th century.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jesus Christ Against Invincible Ignorance</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-invincible-ignorance/jesus-christ-against-invincible-ignorance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-invincible-ignorance/jesus-christ-against-invincible-ignorance/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Perhaps nothing in the New Testament is as clear as the fact that Our Lord Jesus Christ is the Son of God, and that you must believe in Him to have eternal life.&#xA;John 3:16: “For God so loved the world, as to give His only begotten Son: that whosoever believeth in Him, may not perish, but may have life everlasting.”&#xA;John 3:36: “He that believeth in the Son hath life everlasting: but he that believeth not the Son, shall not see life, but the wrath of God abideth on him.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Other Popes And Saints Against Invincible Ignorance</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-invincible-ignorance/saints-against-invincible-ignorance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-invincible-ignorance/saints-against-invincible-ignorance/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Defenders of salvation for the “invincibly ignorant” might be disquieted to hear that two other popes, Pope Benedict XIV and Pope St. Pius X, explicitly reiterated the Church’s dogma that there are certain mysteries of faith about which no one who wishes to be saved can be ignorant. These mysteries are the mysteries of the Trinity and the Incarnation, as it was defined by the Athanasian Creed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pope Pius IX Did Not Teach Salvation Outside The Church</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-invincible-ignorance/pope-pius-ix-salvation-dogma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-invincible-ignorance/pope-pius-ix-salvation-dogma/</guid>
      <description>Singulari Quadame and Quanto Conficiamur Moerore are discussed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sacred Scripture Against Invincible Ignorance</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-invincible-ignorance/sacred-scripture-against-invincible-ignorance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-invincible-ignorance/sacred-scripture-against-invincible-ignorance/</guid>
      <description>And The Evidence of The Immediate Dissemination of The Gospel throughout The World.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Salvation For The “Invincibly Ignorant” Reduced To Its Absurd Principle</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-invincible-ignorance/invincible-ignorance-absurd-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-invincible-ignorance/invincible-ignorance-absurd-principle/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;The theory that “invincible ignorance” saves can also be refuted by reducing it to its absurd principle, which is this: If being ignorant of the Savior could render one worthy of salvation, then Catholics are actually doing non-Christians a disservice in preaching Jesus Christ to them. St. Paul, St. Vincent Ferrer, St. Francis Xavier, Fr. Pierre De Smet, the North American Martyrs and the other countless heroic missionaries in Church history, who suffered mind-boggling hardships to preach the Gospel to the ignorant pagans, were simply making these people more culpable and more guilty before God, according to the modern heresy of salvation for the “invincibly ignorant.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Dogma, Pope Pius IX And Invincible Ignorance</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-invincible-ignorance/dogma-pope-pius-ix-invincible-ignorance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/apologetics/against-invincible-ignorance/dogma-pope-pius-ix-invincible-ignorance/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;OBJECTION- What about Invincible Ignorance?&#xA;ANSWER-&amp;nbsp;&#xA;2 Corinthians 4:3: “And if our gospel be hid, it is hid to them that are lost, in whom the god of this world [Satan] hath blinded the minds of unbelievers, that the light of the gospel of the glory of Christ, who is the image of God, should not shine unto them.”&amp;nbsp;&#xA;Pope Paul III, Council of Trent, Sess.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
