<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Giovanni of Fano&#39;s Commentary on the Rule on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</title>
    <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Giovanni of Fano&#39;s Commentary on the Rule on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 04:44:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 04:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/04/</guid>
      <description>That the Brothers May Not Accept Money</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 10</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 03:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/10/</guid>
      <description>Concerning the admonition and correction of the Brothers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 06:50:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/01/</guid>
      <description>Whether the environment of the Franciscan Rule is safe for salvation Scrupulous Brother – Even though in the previous Dialogue I was educated about the things that are necessary for the salvation of the brothers, I ask that for my greater satisfaction you tell me whether living by this Rule and profession is safe and whether those who observe it can be certain about their personal salvation.&#xA;Mature Brother – My son, as I told you on the previous occasion, hold fast to the conviction that this way of life and the Rule are very safe and whoever observes it will undoubtedly be saved.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prologue</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/00/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 05:59:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/00/</guid>
      <description>Jesus Maria. The most clement and kind God created the rational soul to bestow eternal life on it, and as an illustration of this, He placed mankind in an earthly paradise. To show plainly that He had done this, and that He wished to confer holiness on mankind, He gave them all the necessary means to easily achieve this end, among which recently there are religious Orders, and especially the Friars Minor, in which a person is invited to perform all the works that lead to perfection and his final objective with all ease.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
