<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Society of St. Pius X on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/29-heretical-groups/02-society-of-st-pius-x/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Society of St. Pius X on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/29-heretical-groups/02-society-of-st-pius-x/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Against the Heresies, by Archbishop Marcel Lefebvre</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/29-heretical-groups/02-society-of-st-pius-x/01-against-the-heresies-by-archbishop-marcel-lefebvre/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/29-heretical-groups/02-society-of-st-pius-x/01-against-the-heresies-by-archbishop-marcel-lefebvre/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Page 216: “Evidently, certain distinctions must be made. Souls can be saved in a religion other than the Catholic religion (Protestantism, Islam, Buddhism, etc.), but not by this religion. There may be souls who, not knowing Our Lord, have by the grace of the good Lord, good interior dispositions, who submit to God...But some of these persons make an act of love which implicitly is equivalent to baptism of desire.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baptism of Desire, by Fr. Jean-Marc Rulleau (SSPX)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/29-heretical-groups/02-society-of-st-pius-x/05-baptism-of-desire-jean-marc-rulleau-sspx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/29-heretical-groups/02-society-of-st-pius-x/05-baptism-of-desire-jean-marc-rulleau-sspx/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Recently, the Society of St. Pius X (SSPX – Lefebvrists) published two books attacking the teaching of the Church on Baptism. They spend their time trying to figure out ways for people to be saved without baptism – but to no avail. Baptism of Desire by Fr. Jean-Marc Rulleau was published by the SSPX in 1999, while Is Feeneyism Catholic? by Fr. Francois Laisney was published in 2001.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bishop Fellay says Hindus can be saved</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/29-heretical-groups/02-society-of-st-pius-x/04-bishop-fellay-says-hindus-can-be-saved/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/29-heretical-groups/02-society-of-st-pius-x/04-bishop-fellay-says-hindus-can-be-saved/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Bishop Bernard Fellay, Superior General of SSPX, Conference in Denver, Co., Feb. 18, 2006: “We know that there are two other baptisms, that of desire and that of blood. These produce an invisible but real link with Christ but do not produce all of the effects which are received in the baptism of water… And the Church has always taught that you have people who will be in heaven, who are in the state of grace, who have been saved without knowing the Catholic Church.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Feeneyism Catholic?, by Fr. Francois Laisney (SSPX)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/29-heretical-groups/02-society-of-st-pius-x/06-is-feeneyism-catholic-francois-laisney-sspx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/29-heretical-groups/02-society-of-st-pius-x/06-is-feeneyism-catholic-francois-laisney-sspx/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Published in 2001, Fr. Laisney’s book was a masterpiece in deceit. There are startling and shockingly dishonest things in his book, which will be exposed in the “Lies” section. HERESY:&#xA;On page 21, Fr. Laisney comments on the necessity of explicit faith in Jesus Christ: “… how much is exactly necessary to know explicitly has not been settled.” This statement clearly implies that it has not been settled whether it is necessary for salvation to believe in the Most Holy Trinity and that Jesus Christ is God and man, which is a denial of the Athanasian Creed, not to mention the teaching of St.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Letter to Confused Catholics, by Archbishop Marcel Lefebvre</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/29-heretical-groups/02-society-of-st-pius-x/02-open-letter-to-confused-catholics-by-archbishop-marcel-lefebvre/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/29-heretical-groups/02-society-of-st-pius-x/02-open-letter-to-confused-catholics-by-archbishop-marcel-lefebvre/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Pages 73-74: “Does this mean that no Protestant, no Muslim, no Buddhist or animist will be saved? No, it would be a second error to think that. Those who cry for intolerance in interpreting St. Cyprian’s formula Outside the Church there is no salvation, also reject the Creed, “I accept one baptism for the remission of sins,” and are insufficiently instructed as to what baptism is.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time Bombs of the Second Vatican Council, by Fr. Schmidberger of the SSPX</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/29-heretical-groups/02-society-of-st-pius-x/03-time-bombs-of-the-second-vatican-council-sspx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/29-heretical-groups/02-society-of-st-pius-x/03-time-bombs-of-the-second-vatican-council-sspx/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Fr. Schmidberger (SSPX), Time Bombs of the Second Vatican Council, 2005, p. 10: “Ladies and gentlemen, it is clear that the followers of other religions can be saved under certain conditions, that is to say, if they are in invincible error.”[1]&#xA;Fr. Schmidberger says “it’s clear” that the followers of non-Catholic religions can be saved! No, what is clear is how directly the above statement denies Catholic dogma!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
