<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Heretical Groups Exposed on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/29-heretical-groups/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Heretical Groups Exposed on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/29-heretical-groups/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The CMRI and Other Priests</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/29-heretical-groups/04-cmri-other-priests-against-water-baptism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/29-heretical-groups/04-cmri-other-priests-against-water-baptism/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;Unfortunately, the priests of the CMRI (Congregation of Mary Immaculate Queen) also reject the true meaning of the dogma Outside the Church There is No Salvation. They also adhere to and promote the heretical Protocol 122/49 and hold that those who die as non-Catholics can be saved.&#xA;The CMRI recently published a pamphlet defending “baptism of desire” which implements arguments which have all been thoroughly refuted in this book.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Errors of the Current St. Benedict Center</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/29-heretical-groups/01-errors-current-st-benedict-center/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/29-heretical-groups/01-errors-current-st-benedict-center/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;The St. Benedict Center was founded by Fr. Feeney before Vatican II. As I have documented, it was a beacon of truth on the salvation dogma when the Fr. Feeney controversy erupted in Boston. But the fact that Fr. Feeney staunchly defended this truth on salvation during his day does not mean, of course, that everything he said on the topic was cogent or correct.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Society Of St. Pius V</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/29-heretical-groups/03-sspv-against-water-baptism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/outside-the-church-no-salvation/29-heretical-groups/03-sspv-against-water-baptism/</guid>
      <description>By Brother Peter Dimond, O.S.B.&#xA;Source: vaticancatholic.com&#xA;In our previous magazines we have pointed out the unfortunate fact that the priests of the Society of St. Pius V hold to the heresy that non-Catholics can be saved without the Catholic Faith. For instance, they endorsed the following blatantly heretical question and answer in their publication:&#xA;The Society of St. Pius V, The Roman Catholic, Winter, 2005, p. 54: “Q. Do Catholics believe that non-Catholics cannot be saved.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
