<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Answers to the Most Common Objections Against Sedevacantism on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Answers to the Most Common Objections Against Sedevacantism on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Objection 1): The Gates of Hell cannot prevail against the Church, as Christ said (Matthew 16). He said He would be with His Church all days until the end of the world (Matthew 28). What you are saying is contrary to the promises of Christ.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/01-gates-of-hell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/01-gates-of-hell/</guid>
      <description>2007/01/19&#xA;Answer: No, indefectibility (the promise of Christ to always be with His Church, and that the gates of Hell will not prevail against it) means that the Church will, until the end of time, remain essentially what she is.&amp;nbsp; The indefectibility of the Church requires that at least a remnant of the Church will exist until the end of the world, and that a true pope will never authoritatively teach error to the entire Church.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Objection 10): Pope Pius XII declared in Vacantis Apostolicae Sedis that a cardinal, no matter what excommunication he’s under, can be elected pope.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/10-cardinal-elects-excommunicated-pope/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/10-cardinal-elects-excommunicated-pope/</guid>
      <description>2007/01/19&#xA;Pope Pius XII, Vacantis Apostolicae Sedis, Dec. 8, 1945: &#34;34. None of the cardinals may in any way, or by pretext of any excommunication, suspension, or interdict whatsoever, or of any other ecclesiastical impediment, be excluded in the active and passive election of the Supreme Pontiff. We hereby suspend such censures solely for the purposes of the said election; at other times they are to remain in vigor (AAS 38 [1946], p.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Objection 11): What does it matter whether or not Benedict XVI/Francis is a pope? The issue does not concern me.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/11-popes-or-not-why-does-it-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/11-popes-or-not-why-does-it-matter/</guid>
      <description>2007/01/19&#xA;Answer: If whether or not Benedict XVI is a pope does not matter, then the non-Catholicism of the Vatican II sect does not matter, the New Mass doesn’t matter, etc. One cannot separate one from the other. You cannot separate pope and Church. Furthermore, to maintain that Benedict XVI is the head of the Catholic Church is to assert that the gates of Hell have prevailed against Her.&#xA;Further, to obstinately recognize Benedict XVI as the pope is to commit a sin against the Faith; for it is to assert that one has the true Faith who, in fact, is a manifest heretic and apostate against it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Objection 12): How could the entire Church and all the cardinals recognize an antipope, such as in the case of John XXIII (1958-1963)?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/12-cardinals-john-xxiii-antipope-1958/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/12-cardinals-john-xxiii-antipope-1958/</guid>
      <description>2007/01/19&#xA;Answer: Pope Paul IV declared that Catholics could not accept such a heretical claimant, even if obedience were given to him by &#34;all&#34; – indicating by such a statement that all giving obedience to such an antipope is a possibility. Pope Paul IV, Bull Cum ex Apostolatus Officio, Feb. 15, 1559: “6. In addition, [by this Our Constitution, which is to remain valid in perpetuity We enact, determine, decree and define:] that if ever at any time it shall appear that… the Roman Pontiff, prior to his promotion or his elevation as Cardinal or Roman Pontiff, has deviated from the Catholic Faith or fallen into some heresy… (ii) it shall not be possible for it to acquire validity (nor for it to be said that it has thus acquired validity) through the acceptance of the office, of consecration, of subsequent authority, nor through possession of administration, nor through the putative enthronement of a Roman Pontiff, or Veneration, or obedience accorded to such by all, nor through the lapse of any period of time in the foregoing situation;…”</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Objection 13): John XXII was a heretic, who was even denounced by Cardinal Orsini as a heretic, yet he remained the pope.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/13-pope-john-xxii-not-a-heretic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/13-pope-john-xxii-not-a-heretic/</guid>
      <description>2007/01/19&#xA;Chris Ferrara, “Opposing the Sedevacantist Enterprise,” Catholic Family News, August 2005, p. 21: “Compare the [Sedevacantist] Enterprise’s lack of success in finding ‘manifest’ heresy in the pronouncements of the conciliar popes with the historical example of Pope John XXII. In 1331, certain French theologians and Cardinal Orsini denounced John XXII as a heretic when, in a series of sermons, he taught that the souls of the blessed departed, after finishing their appointed time in Purgatory, do not see God until after the last judgment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Objection 14): Pope Honorius was condemned for heresy by a general council after his death, yet the Church does not consider him to have ceased to be pope, even though he was accused of heresy during his reign.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/14-pope-honorius-condemned/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/14-pope-honorius-condemned/</guid>
      <description>2007/01/19&#xA;Pope Eugene IV, Council of Florence, ex cathedra: “The Holy Roman Church firmly believes, professes and preaches that all those who are outside the Catholic Church, not only pagans but also Jews or heretics and schismatics …”[1]&#xA;The case of Pope Honorius doesn’t prove that a heretic can be the pope. In condemning Pope Honorius as a heretic after his death, the III Council of Constantinople made no statement – nor has the Church ever made a statement – that he remained pope until his death.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Objection 15): The Church and the hierarchy will always be visible. If the Vatican II Church is not the true Catholic Church, then the Church and hierarchy are no longer visible.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/15-hierarchy-visibility-of-the-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/15-hierarchy-visibility-of-the-church/</guid>
      <description>2007/01/19&#xA;Answer: 1) People misunderstand in what the visibility of the Church consists; 2) the Vatican II sect cannot be the visible Church of Christ; and 3) the Vatican II sect denies this very teaching on the visibility of the Church.&#xA;No one denies that the Catholic Church could cease to exist in all the countries of the world except one. The visibility of the Church does not require that the faithful or the hierarchy be seen in every single geographical location around the globe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Objection 16): The Vatican II popes haven’t taught manifest heresy, because their statements are ambiguous and require commentary.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/16-heretics-ambiguous-statements/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/16-heretics-ambiguous-statements/</guid>
      <description>2007/01/19&#xA;Chris Ferrara, Catholic Family News, “Opposing the Sedevacantist Enterprise, Part II,” Oct. 2005, p. 8: “Now that which is manifest – i.e., plain, evident, obvious, unmistakable and undoubted – requires no explanation. The very quality of not needing to be explained is what makes a thing manifest. Thus, before the Enterprise can even get to first base, it must show us not merely papal statements made openly, but statements whose alleged heresy requires no explanation to demonstrate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Objection 17): Both the 1917 and 1983 Codes of Canon Law teach that a declaration is needed for one to lose his office due to heresy.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/17-codes-of-canon-law-1917-1983/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/17-codes-of-canon-law-1917-1983/</guid>
      <description>2007/01/19&#xA;Chris Ferrara, ”A Challenge to the Sedevacantist Enterprise, Part II,” The Remnant, Sept. 30, 2005, p. 18: “Indeed, both the 1917 and 1983 codes of canon law provide that no one may insist that an ecclesiastical office has been lost due to heresy unless this has been established by a declaration of the competent authority.”[1]&#xA;Answer: This is simply not true. Antipope John Paul II’s heretical and invalid 1983 Code states that such a declaration is necessary in Canon 194 § 3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Objection 18): The Council of Constance condemned the idea that a heretic would cease to be the pope.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/18-council-of-constance-john-hus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/18-council-of-constance-john-hus/</guid>
      <description>2007/01/19&#xA;Errors of John Hus, Condemned by the Council of Constance: “#20. If the Pope is wicked and especially if he is foreknown (as a reprobate), then as Judas, the Apostle, he is of the devil, a thief, and a son of perdition, and he is not the head of the holy militant Church, since he is not a member of it.&#34;[1] – Condemned&#xA;Answer: No, the Council of Constance didn’t condemn the idea that a heretic would cease to be the pope at all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Objection 19): The Joint Declaration with the Lutherans is not manifest heresy because John Paul II and Benedict XVI didn’t sign it.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/19-joint-declaration-lutherans-john-paul-ii-benedict-xvi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/19-joint-declaration-lutherans-john-paul-ii-benedict-xvi/</guid>
      <description>2007/01/19&#xA;Answer: The Joint Declaration with the Lutherans by itself proves that the Vatican II “popes” are non-Catholic antipopes. The fact that John Paul II and Benedict XVI neither wrote the document nor signed it is completely irrelevant. They both approved of it publicly numerous times, and agreed with it. John Paul II, Jan. 19, 2004, At a Meeting with Lutherans From Finland: “… I wish to express my gratitude for the ecumenical progress made between Catholics and Lutherans in the five years since the signing of the Joint Declaration on the Doctrine of Justification.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Objection 2): What’s your authority for making these judgments? Your use of dogmatic statements is private interpretation.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/02-dogmatic-statements/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/02-dogmatic-statements/</guid>
      <description>2007/01/19&#xA;Answer: The authority a Catholic has to determine that heretics are not members of the Church is Catholic dogma, which teaches us that those who depart from the Faith are considered alien to the Church.&#xA;Pope Leo XIII, Satis Cognitum (# 9), June 29, 1896:&#xA;“The practice of the Church has always been the same, as is shown by the unanimous teaching of the Fathers, who were wont to hold as outside Catholic communion, AND ALIEN TO THE CHURCH, WHOEVER WOULD RECEDE IN THE LEAST DEGREE FROM ANY POINT OF DOCTRINE PROPOSED BY HER AUTHORITATIVE MAGISTERIUM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Objection 3): You cannot know if someone is a heretic or denounce him as such without a trial and declaratory sentence.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/03-declaration-sentence-against-heretics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/03-declaration-sentence-against-heretics/</guid>
      <description>2007/01/19&#xA;Answer: Not so. The declaratory sentence which follows an automatic excommunication is merely a legal recognition of something which already exists. If this were not true, the automatic excommunication would be meaningless. Canon 2314, 1917 Code of Canon Law: “All apostates from the Christian faith and each and every heretic or schismatic: 1) Incur ipso facto [by that very fact] excommunication…”[1]&#xA;The excommunicated person is already severed from the Church.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Objection 4): What about material heresy? Can’t the Vatican II Popes only be material heretics?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/04-material-heresy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/04-material-heresy/</guid>
      <description>2007/01/19&#xA;Answer: A “material” heretic is a Catholic erring in good faith about a dogmatic issue.&amp;nbsp; The Vatican II antipopes are without doubt real heretics.&amp;nbsp; They cannot be material heretics (Catholics erring in good faith) for many reasons, most important among those reasons being: 1) they don’t hold the essential mysteries of Faith; 2) they reject obvious dogmas of which they are fully aware.&#xA;“Material heretic” is a term used by theologians to describe a Catholic erring in good faith regarding some Church teaching, who has not denied it deliberately.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Objection 5): The Church cannot exist without a pope, or at least it cannot exist for 40 years without a pope, as Sedevacantists say…</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/05-church-can-exist-without-a-pope/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/05-church-can-exist-without-a-pope/</guid>
      <description>2007/01/19&#xA;Answer: The Church has existed for years without a pope, and does so every time a pope dies. The Church has experienced a papal interregnum (i.e. period without a pope) over 200 different times in Church history. The longest papal interregnum (before the Vatican II apostasy) was between Pope St. Marcellinus (296-304) and Pope St. Marcellus (308-309). It lasted for more than three and a half years.[i] Further, theologians teach that the Church can exist for even decades without a pope.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Objection 6): Vatican I’s definitions on the perpetuity of the Papal Office contradict the claims of the sedevacantists.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/06-perpetual-successors/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/06-perpetual-successors/</guid>
      <description>2021/01/19&#xA;Answer: Vatican I’s dogmas don’t contradict a vacancy of the Papal See; in fact, it’s only those who reject the Vatican II antipopes who can consistently accept these papal dogmas, since Benedict XVI utterly rejects them.&#xA;ANSWERS TO SPECIFIC PASSAGES FROM VATICAN I CITED BY NONSEDEVACANTISTS – AND THE ABSURDITY OF A “POPE” WHO DOESN’T BELIEVE IN VATICAN I&#xA;People attempting to refute sedevacantism often cite three passages from Vatican I.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Objection 7): No one can judge the Holy See… thus the Vatican II popes are true popes.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/07-no-one-can-judge-the-holy-see/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/07-no-one-can-judge-the-holy-see/</guid>
      <description>2007/01/19&#xA;Pope St. Nicholas, epistle (8), Proposueramus quidem, 865: “… Neither by Augustus, nor by all the clergy, nor by religious, nor by the people will the judge be judged… ‘The first seat will not be judged by anyone.’”[1]&#xA;This is what “No one can judge the Holy See” means. It does not refer to recognizing a manifest heretic who claims to be the pope as one who is not a true pope.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Objection 8): St. Robert Bellarmine said that one cannot depose a pope, but that one can licitly resist him. Sedevacantists judge, punish and depose the pope…</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/08-bellarmine-resist-a-pope/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/08-bellarmine-resist-a-pope/</guid>
      <description>2007/01/19&#xA;St. Robert Bellarmine, De Romano Pontifice, Book II, Chap. 29: “Just as it is licit to resist the Pontiff who attacks the body, so also is it licit to resist him who attacks souls or destroys the civil order or above all, tries to destroy the Church. I say that it is licit to resist him by not doing what he orders and by impeding the execution of his will.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Objection 9): Pope Liberius gave in to the Arian heretics and excommunicated St. Athanasius, yet he remained the pope…</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/09-pope-liberius-arians/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/apologetics/sedevacantism/objections/09-pope-liberius-arians/</guid>
      <description>2007/01/19&#xA;Answer: It is not true that Pope Liberius gave in to the Arians, signed any Arian formula, or even excommunicated St. Athanasius. Pope Liberius was a staunch defender of the truth during the Arian crisis, but his return from exile gave some the idea that he had compromised, when, in fact, he had not. We quote Pope Pius IX.&#xA;Pope Pius IX, Quartus Supra (# 16), January 6, 1873, On False Accusations:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
