<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chapter 1 on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</title>
    <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/01/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chapter 1 on Extra Ecclesiam Nulla Salus</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 05:24:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/01/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The intention of Saint Francis regarding the interpretation of the Rule</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/01/04-interpretation-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 05:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/01/04-interpretation-rule/</guid>
      <description>Scrupulous Brother – What do you think was Saint Francis’ intention with respect to the interpretation of the Rule? Mature Brother – Note well that Saint Francis said in his Testament that he wanted the Rule to be understood simply and observed in the same way. He says that the Lord revealed it to him. Although with good intentions, the Pope said that we were not bound to observe the Testament, we must still hold it in the highest respect and observe it where possible, as Alvarus says, since that is where our Father sets out his intentions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whether the way of life of the Observants is safe and according to the mind of Saint Francis</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/01/03-way-of-life-of-observants-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 20:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/01/03-way-of-life-of-observants-safe/</guid>
      <description>Scrupulous Brother – [&amp;hellip;] I would like to know whether the way of life followed by our brothers known as the Observants (among whom I am presently living) follows the mind of Saint Francis and can be followed safely according to the conscience of the brothers. Mature Brother – What makes you have doubts?&#xA;Scrupulous Brother – The four things which you already mentioned to me before. The more I saw the novel way of life and continual change, the more I began to have doubts, especially when, following your explanation, I saw that you had left the “family” and gone to the Capuchin reform.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How many Rules did Saint Francis Write?</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/01/02-how-many-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 19:59:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/01/02-how-many-rules/</guid>
      <description>Scrupulous Brother – Did our Father Saint Francis write more than one Rule? Mature Brother – At different times, he wrote three. The first was written around the third year of his conversion and contained twenty-four chapters. It was approved by Innocent III without a Bull, as Pope Honorius mentions in the foreword to our Rule. He wrote the second around the eleventh year of his conversion. It was approved by the same Pope with a Bull, and as the Book of Conformities states, it was concealed or destroyed by Brother Elias.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whether the environment of the Franciscan Rule is safe for salvation</title>
      <link>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/01/01-rule-safe-for-salvation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 19:43:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eens-en.netlify.app/religious-life/friars-minors/capuchins/john-of-fano-commentary-rule/01/01-rule-safe-for-salvation/</guid>
      <description>Scrupulous Brother – Even though in the previous Dialogue I was educated about the things that are necessary for the salvation of the brothers, I ask that for my greater satisfaction you tell me whether living by this Rule and profession is safe and whether those who observe it can be certain about their personal salvation.&#xA;Mature Brother – My son, as I told you on the previous occasion, hold fast to the conviction that this way of life and the Rule are very safe and whoever observes it will undoubtedly be saved.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
